With more Isaac, and Lazarus, and Azazel, and all the others I can't name off the top of the head.
Guys, I have a confession to make.
I was playing Isaac all night off stream.
I'm kidding.
But I was thinking about Isaac all night off stream.
Guys, I can't stop thinking about it, man.
I just want to play all the time.
I keep thinking about this game.
It's so stupid.
It's such a simple little stupid game.
With poops.
And Whore of Babylon, and I don't even know what else.
Mean mothers?
I like that everyone was just like, what?
Come on now.
Oh yeah, the tit-squirt, that's true.
That's so weird.
Guys, what is that drawing supposed to be?
Can we get this settled?
Once and for all.
What is that tit-squirt drawing actually showing?
I need to understand.
It's pooping butts?
What?
But why is the butt in the chest area?
It's two guys shitting on Isaac?
But how?
They're leaned over?
180 head turn, just perspective.
Huh.
I gotta look at that with a new perspective then.
Because man, is that drawing not very good at showing what it's supposed to show them.
Maybe it's just me.
I could be the only one.
Oh man.
You pressed F5 to get a new perspective?
I'm sure you're gonna get the same.
Maybe a bit more recent.
Not as delayed.
Drink water, y'all.
You're so right.
I brought water.
In fact, I just came home from a pretty long walk as part of my recent health routine.
8 kilometers, was it?
Not too bad.
I have some shitty shoes because my feet were hurting after that.
Not because it was exhausting.
But because, I don't know, the fucking shoes were shitty.
I need to get back to where I was a couple years ago when I ran 10k's and 15k's and all that.
No, we're not talking about Project Hail Mary.
That was a very specific question.
That's more about your feet.
Okay, I'm barefoot right now.
Because I just took a shower.
I'm actually sitting in... since you're asking, I may as well give you more information.
I pretty much look like Charlie from YouTube.
I sit in those bathing... I was about to say bathing suit.
But you know the bathing shorts?
With the very colorful flowers?
That's my setup right now.
I am actually wearing a beige shirt, not quite a white shirt.
My hair is getting long, but not as long as Charlie's.
Oh, man.
Guys, I'm sorry.
I would love to chat all day, but I kind of want to just play.
I know I'm selfish.
I want to get in there.
Here we go.
File one.
Thank God I managed to delete file two in time, so you didn't see I was playing all night.
Just kidding.
Okay, so what am I doing today?
Last time was Lazarus.
This one is new, Eden.
There's two Eden tokens.
That's very interesting.
I wish it was three Eden tokens.
I hate that it's two.
I don't even know what that means.
Sure.
We could random.
Should we random?
We also have a yum heart.
I don't know what that symbol is supposed to be with the X on it.
It's like a little cartridge or something.
Maybe a box?
Lock foot.
Let's try a cane.
With one eye.
We have a wind streak going right now, ladies and gentlemen.
We should keep it up.
Oh, you know what?
Let's start the day off with a Zazel.
I want to keep the wind streak going.
Just one a Zazel game.
Just one and then we go for new ones.
We got to get back into it, you know?
Okay, okay.
I'm actually not going to go in there.
I was about to say I'm going to go in there, but I'm not.
Oh, it's already broken.
Look at this.
Huh?
You got pushed?
That's new.
Also, last time we unlocked some kind of secret sauce.
We could see the butt of Isaac when he went into the chest and he recovered some kind of sauce.
And then after that, he started going crazy.
He was like, oh, what have I done by recovering the sauce?
You know?
So I wonder what that's all about.
Maybe we'll get an answer to that today.
So far, man, I am already looking forward to playing Isaac and I'm already playing it.
How weird is that?
That's such a weird feeling.
Okay.
Um, hmm.
Oh, wait, I had a thing over here.
Let me go get that.
In fact, I should always get that first.
Crack the sky!
Holy white death!
What's that all about?
Summon five beams of light from above that deal heavy damage to enemies.
Okay.
So it's a usable item.
We have to remember to use items today.
No more missing items.
Someone was drawing Isaac with his head off on the floor there.
You see that?
Very mean.
Extremely mean stuff.
Oh, oopsie daisy.
I have to remember how to play Azazel.
Man, imagine getting a streak of two.
That would be crazy.
Um, oh, the boss is here.
And that's a pill.
Oh, yeah, I could just fly in there.
I was about to blow it up.
Amazing.
Teleport to the starting room.
Uh, oh, wait, no, no, I want the pill.
Try it.
Balls of steel.
I don't know what it means.
What could balls of steel mean?
Oh, we got extra hearts!
There it is.
That's what that means.
Okay, now we have this card.
Let's
go.
We could go to the shop.
I guess we have nothing to lose by going in here.
Bogo bombs.
That's the one I had last time.
All bomb pickups become double bombs.
What's that one?
It's a question mark.
Okay, so I think tarot cards are just like pills.
You know, it's randomized at the start of each run.
That's the only explanation.
Uh, I'm actually gonna go in here.
Wait, I didn't take damage.
Why is that?
But I take damage on the way out.
Yeah, okay.
That's interesting why that is that way.
I think when you're flying, you don't take damage when you enter, but you do when you exit.
And I think it's the flying status that's doing it.
This was a short floor.
Look at that.
Almost no rooms.
Time for gurglings.
I'm gonna gurgle them up.
Oh, no.
I gotta be careful here.
I can't lose any hearts.
This is actually one of the big things about Azazel.
You want to be conservative with that.
Shit, I was not.
Ah, nice!
No!
That's fine.
We didn't get touched on the black hearts.
Or okay, what's this?
Booster pack, spawns five random cards on pickup.
That's good.
Whoa.
Emperor?
Doubles I6 keys.
Oh, I have no keys.
That's so bad.
Oh, we can get keys, but wait a minute.
Doubles I6 red hearts.
Okay, there's none.
Oh, that is actually so cool.
Dude, the two of hearts could be insane later on.
If you have like five red hearts and you do this, you have ten.
That's mega good.
Two of clubs, Doubles I6 bombs.
Okay, I guess I'm just gonna take some bombs then.
It's Q.
Nice.
The Joker teleports to the devil or angel room.
That's good as well.
I'm gonna take this.
Give me keys, nice.
Two of hearts, man.
I would love to just have that on me for later.
Teleport to the boss room.
Oh, I didn't mean to pick that up.
I'm gonna do the Joker.
Ooh.
Wait, three blue hearts?
What does that mean?
Why are they blue and not red?
Creates a trap door to the next floor or to a crawl space?
I don't know what a crawl space is.
Oh, don't you dare shoot me.
Wow, it actually dropped the heart.
Insane.
I'm not gonna take it.
It doesn't seem that good.
Okay, nice.
I can still grab this.
I'm gonna hold on to the two of hearts until we somehow get items that give us hearts.
I'm gonna duplicate it.
Oh, it's gonna be sick.
I hope my plan can actually work in practice.
We'll have to see.
Uh-oh, it's the recursive dream.
This doesn't bode well.
We got 100% on demon mode right now.
We are maximum demon.
You know what that means, right?
We can't lose.
Oh!
Okay.
We got a bomb.
I'm gonna play a little more slow today than usual.
I wanna be more observant.
Oh, no.
Okay, he poops that stuff.
Good to know.
Okay, spiders are gone.
Oh, I think the poop or the fart just pushes me.
It doesn't do any damage.
That's good.
Come here.
I'm gonna have to take out all the fires.
Yeah, look at that.
Beautiful.
Okay, we got a long room here.
These are usually kind of scary.
Okay, whoa, he hit me.
Somehow.
I didn't even see the projectile.
What's that?
Spawn 6 troll bombs.
I could hold on to that for now and then just come back and grab this card later.
Yeah.
Troll bombs.
So far, so good.
I have to remember, I don't have a lot of range at the beginning with this guy.
In fact, it's quite a problem at the start.
We do have five coins.
I could go in there, but I'm not gonna.
Not yet.
Oh, I can't believe it.
It's tough.
Okay, okay.
Let's see what we have in here.
What's that?
15 coins for that one.
Nope.
Oh, wait a minute.
I also had this active.
Someone's five beams of light from above.
I gotta try that.
Oh, okay, so it's just around Isaac.
Or around Lazarus.
Azazel, I mean.
I thought it was just anywhere in the room where we had enemies.
Not too bad.
Oh, this is a nice room.
What's that?
Sister Maggie, friends till the end.
Okay.
Unjoined, familiar that fires tears for six damage.
Oh, shoots automatically at fire too.
That's funny.
Wait, did I gain a black heart back?
I thought I had only one heart.
Perhaps I just misunderstood what was going on.
Okay, I want to find more of those secret rooms.
Oh, wait, I should have boosted terrain.
This is something I keep forgetting when I'm Azazel.
The fact that I can do stuff like this is massive.
Oh, we got big ice.
This is a perfect level for it, though.
Ah, my god, come here.
Why are they so defensive?
Okay, good.
Oh, man.
It's not going too well.
But I'm managing.
I just want to see if there's any special rocks as well.
Doesn't look like it.
Okay, looks clean.
Wrath.
No problem for Isaac.
Dude, I'm getting so many bombs.
So many bombs.
Should I just try and blow shit up?
I'm going to blow this wall up, I have a feeling.
No!
Okay, this one, I have a feeling.
Oi!
I told you I had a feeling!
Oh my god!
Oh, that was a lot of coins!
Wow!
Okay, guys, I have a feeling.
Wait, I have a feeling now.
The door stop!
Oh!
I'm an idiot.
That's the same room I was in.
Well, okay.
That's fine.
Whoopsie doopsie.
That was a mistake.
But my feeling was correct nonetheless.
The feeling was on point.
It's time for the boss.
I'm going to keep my...
Okay.
Troll bombs, I guess.
Yeah.
Actually, wait a minute, let me try something.
We had a massive room with a lot of rocks.
Wait, whoa!
Okay.
Where's this big room up here?
What if I just do it like here?
The tower.
Oh, it's totally random, okay.
Hmm, okay.
I thought it would be like around my character at least.
But it seems extremely random.
Okay, here we go.
We're going to use our active item in here.
Let's get ready.
The haunt.
I forgot what he did.
Oh, wait, that's this guy.
I'm going to kill the first dude down here.
And then we're going to activate this thing.
Oh, it's super good!
The foreskin.
Nice.
I cannot...
I did not get hit there, but I did get hit.
One health!
Huge.
That is actually massive.
We also have a demon room.
The problem is, if I go in there, they want me to sacrifice health for it.
I mean, I can just have a look, I guess.
Whoa.
The Book of Belial gained damage for the current room.
No, no, no, that's horrible.
That's an active.
This is an unknown item.
Mmm...
I mean, some could say that it's a good idea to pick it up just to see what it is.
Just to identify it, right?
Wait, why is there no heart on it?
Oh.
But I still lost the health.
Okay, weird.
Gympie.
Oh, I see, it's a gimp suit.
Chance to drop a soul heart when taking damage.
Chance to drop a half red heart when killing an enemy.
Chance increases with luck.
Oh!
That sounds pretty useful for me.
Especially when I don't have a lot of HP to begin with.
The problem, though, is that I'm kinda...
How do you say it's low on HP?
Exactly, that's how you say it.
What's this?
I think I'm gonna buy this.
Spider Mod.
Mod Body.
It's a spider baby.
Familiar that inflicts random status effects on contact.
Displays health bars and damage numbers for all...
What?!
Chance to spawn a battery or blue spider?
That sounds incredible!
We get health bars.
Whoa!
Okay.
Color me intrigued.
I gotta see that in action.
Oh, the PP.
I gotta be careful because I could easily die here.
Uh, you know what, maybe I should use my two of hearts.
No, I'm gonna wait for one more heart.
Maybe I'm being too risky here.
There's health bars!
That's insane!
Oh yeah, I can just fly!
Let's not forget.
What?
That's so weird.
Haha!
Whoa, it even shows how much damage I do!
Oh, that is so cool!
Huge fan of this one!
I'm so glad I got it.
Wait, I can only shoot...
Oh, okay, okay, okay.
Wow.
They only shoot along the side they're facing.
Cool.
Oh, we got a pill.
Ex-lax.
It didn't affect my health, it didn't change my stats.
Maybe it's like a damaging debuff on the floor for the enemy.
Man, you don't want to be walking on shit.
Right?
That's bad.
How did you not die?
Whoa, they regenerate health.
This is actually great information to get.
I'm gaining information here.
About the enemies because of this.
Shoot your shot, man.
Okay.
I keep thinking that spider is an enemy, but it's not.
Whoa.
Get blown up!
It didn't do anything, that's crazy.
How useless was that?
Come on, kill him.
My familiar needs to stop shooting.
Oh wait, I guess I...
No!
There's no way that it's like that.
That is whor- okay, one more.
One more Azazel.
That is horrible.
I didn't even realize I only had half an HP.
Huge mistake there.
But at least we identified some key items.
So if I see that again, I will actually take it immediately.
Because it seems insane.
Oh no!
It's already going terribly!
And I can't predict their movement!
Ah!
Okay, there we go.
I want this.
What- uh, Lard?
Oh!
Whoa!
That is crazy!
Bucket of Lard is actually insanity!
Holy moly!
This is already a much better run.
Just because of that.
Uh, something's going on here.
What's going on here?
Very mysterious.
What's this?
We don't know what it is, it's new.
Man, I thought about donating in the last run, but I didn't do it.
I should have done it.
The thought crossed my mind, you know.
Oh!
Here we go!
We got a rock here!
Look at this one!
That's the one!
I can't bomb it, though.
Uh, I'll be back.
We gotta find bombs.
Wait, oh my god, there's nowhere to go.
Guess I'll go in here.
No, this is gonna consume a black heart, isn't it?
I mean, I guess it is what it is.
Shit!
This has got to be it.
No, I can't!
Can I access this?
Oh, I can!
Uh, the fool where journey begins.
Retrovision, that sucks.
Experimental kill.
Here's up HP down, that's not good.
That is horrible!
I can't even get the frickin' rock!
Not looking good!
Here we go.
Huge!
Now we wait.
Playing it safe.
Yeah, there we go.
That is what I should be doing against this bot.
Just play it ultra safe.
A snack!
Ooh, huge!
Very nice!
No bombs though!
Crap!
I can't access that special rock!
Wait.
How sad is that?
Ultra sad.
Okay.
Uh, let's go.
Can I skip D somehow?
Cellar two.
Ho ho!
Lemon party?
I mean, it's producing creep.
Maybe this is, uh, you know, something that slows enemies or makes them slip or something.
You know?
Oh god.
Come closer.
Nice.
Wait, we got another rock here!
Look at this!
It even has an X on it!
I need bombs!
I need it now!
Wait, I'm safe here.
Yeah.
Gimme.
No bombs for me, huh?
Wait, am I flying over the fire?
I don't think I am.
Okay.
Abuse the terrain.
Good.
Uh,
oh, there's a poop here.
Nice!
Huge!
Uh, I could enter here now.
PhD.
I wonder what that does.
We gotta try and buy it.
Gives us access to higher paying jobs.
Here.
Nice.
Uh, let's see this room.
Anything suspicious?
I don't think so.
I need to be more aggressive with my playstyle, I think.
Not as afraid, you know?
Aw, no way.
Okay, well, there goes the black hearts.
It's time for the red hearts to reign supreme.
Like, how crazy is it that I haven't found a single bomb in two runs?
Like, what is going on right now?
There's gotta be a bomb in here.
Nope.
Uh, two keys needed for that one?
No, I need this.
A mask.
I think I've had that one before.
Looks like the one from, uh, The Mask with Jim Carrey.
50% chance to block projectiles!
Whoa!
That is actually...
That is, like, straight up like a half damage reduction, pretty much.
Well, not quite, but almost.
More things to make me rich?
Still no bombs, though, this is insanity.
Where are the bombs?
Oh, wait, we have a room down here.
Let's check that out.
No, it's closed.
Fine.
I still have not figured out the...
factor that decides when that opens.
I'm gonna beat the boss and come back.
See what happens then.
Pin!
One, two, three, four.
Okay, he shoots projectiles.
Bombs?
Okay, yeah.
Oh, this is not too bad at all.
Oi, oi, oi, careful now.
Beautiful!
Look at that one!
That's cool!
Eyedrops, more tears, increases fire rate.
That sounds amazing.
But I wonder how fire rate works.
Oh, is it just charge speed or what?
So here's the thing, I wonder if I pick one of these up, is it gonna consume my fucking blue heart or not?
Motherfucker, red fires just messed me up.
I keep forgetting.
I'm gonna... I want this one.
Sulphur, temporary demon form.
Okay, so we got demon and we lost angel.
That makes sense, I guess.
Leviathan grants brimstone for the current room.
Oh, it's an active!
Boo!
Activating twice in the same room grants a more powerful version of brimstone.
But what is that even?
What is brimstone?
I'm gonna take this one, because I think what's gonna happen, I'm gonna end up with half a red heart.
Motherfucker!
Why is it blue?
Oh, it's over then.
GG.
It's over.
Goddammit.
Dark bomb.
Familiar that consumes red heart pickups?
No!
And drops black hearts.
Oh, okay, that's fine, I guess.
Pills cards, blue spiders, a hostile spiders will turn.
Yikes.
Goddammit.
I'm gonna activate this brimstone now, in the first room with the enemies.
Just because I am so close to death.
The good news is, even though I'm dying a lot here, I'm getting a lot of new items identified, you know?
And that's important.
Okay, here we go.
We also have the fool, we can't escape, if need be.
Woah!
Infinite laser!
Yo, that's dope as hell.
Is that what brimstone is?
Infinite laser.
Or maybe just infinite range, because if I was on Isaac, it would have been tears, right?
Okay, here we go.
Oh god!
Wow.
Oi, oi, oi.
Uh, where are my heart drops, so this guy can consume them and make more.
I'm not gonna go into the big room, I hate those corridors, they're dangerous.
Oi!
Wait, how did I not take damage just now?
Oh, was it the mask?
Oh!
I think it was the mask.
Oh, that's a friend.
Oh no.
Okay, now this guy.
Wow.
Uh, not in there.
I'm gonna activate the brimstone in here.
Okay, it was actually not needed.
Dude, this isn't...
Imagine having this 24-7.
Ho, ho, ho, ho!
A bomb!
I can't believe it!
We found a bomb!
That is unreal.
Oh, there's also a bomb here.
Wow.
Oh wait, that's not infinite anymore!
No, it's over!
Fuck!
Okay.
Maybe we do one last Azazel run.
Okay, three is the magic number.
I feel like we're making good progress on items right now.
This is good progress.
It's all fine.
All that other stuff was warm up.
Now we're back in it, you know?
God, I actually kind of love restarting.
Something about it.
It's like a new whole world of possibilities.
Oh, we got rock!
Let me find a bomb!
I swear to God, if there's not gonna be a bomb again, I'm gonna actually cry.
I will become Isaac.
I need bombs.
There's a heart there.
Useless for me.
Oi, yo, yo.
A key?
Okay.
Better than nothing.
Dude, it actually smells like poop right now.
But I think it's because Jackie was pooping in the other room and some of the circulation made the poop come in here.
It's not that bad at all, but I can just slightly smell it, you know?
So I'm really immersed in the game right now.
I can smell the poop.
Down here.
Oh yeah, we can just go through the rocks, baby!
Still no bombs.
There's a bomb here.
But that's not gonna help me, is it?
What's that?
A shiny rock.
It shines for its brothers.
Tinted rocks and rocks covering crawl spaces will occasionally gleam.
Tinted rocks.
So I guess those are the special rocks.
The secret rocks.
I mean, I don't need that.
What I need is bombs!
I can already spot them.
I don't need help with that.
Please just die, sir.
Jesus.
Thank you.
That's the boss.
Not yet.
I wonder if the...
distinguishing effects on it.
So that one is...
Okay, it's blinking, I know, but I don't have a bomb!
God damn!
Where are the bombs?
Oh, I didn't mean for that to happen.
A brain worm.
Missed shots turned 90 degrees to target enemies.
Wait, what?
I'd rather have this.
I want to find secrets.
Kill him.
The magician.
More range.
Homing shots.
Best friend.
Friends till the end.
Places a decoy that draws enemies to it and... Oh, that one.
I'm not a big fan of that.
You know what I could do?
I could enter that...
Oh, no, no, that's not that room.
I was going to say we enter the room where we take no damage entering, then we teleport out.
Well, we don't have one of those rooms, so...
RIP!
I'm going to the money room.
Tarot cloth?
That was the effect of most cards.
Well, I can't afford it.
So why am I even looking at it?
Boss time!
Yeah, I wish I could do something about that rock, but I can't.
Because this game has no rocks today or bombs today for some reason.
It's absolute insanity, actually.
Larry!
Oh, no!
What a start!
Why is it not drawing enemies in?
Okay!
Okay.
The belts.
More speed, nice.
Very nice.
Oh, oh, that's a good one!
Amazing!
We gain an extra heart now.
Very cool.
This is actually a decent start.
Seller two.
Oh, whoa!
Why am I going around like this?
What's happening?
Why am I doing this?
Go!
A little piece of shit down there.
Can I hit it from here?
Oh, I'm totally cheating with that!
What the heck?
I love it!
Oi, yoi.
Nice.
Finally the bombs!
Let's see if there's any suspicious rocks now.
I'm really gonna look.
Jump.
Nice.
We wait for it to jump, then we go.
Huge!
Uh,
what do we have here?
Any suspicious rocks?
Or tinted rocks?
Uh, we could go to the boss.
Nah.
Why would you ever go to the boss first if you have the opportunity to clear out the rest?
That's what I don't understand.
Did you actually hit me?
I don't think you did.
Come here.
Are you crying?
Beautiful.
Yeah!
Oh, huge!
Let me look at these rocks.
Everything looks pretty normal to me.
Yep, nothing suspicious here.
A jar of flies?
Uh, not a big fan of that.
See, now's the time I need the tinted rocks.
We got a couple rooms down here still.
Ooh!
Oh!
It was just the sound of the spikes popping out!
I don't know why I just got so scared.
Okay, nice.
Huge!
A host hat!
Blast resistance.
Places a host on Isaac's head, which makes Isaac immune to explosion damage.
Chance to block enemy shots and fire three bullets back.
Wait!
Oh, I don't have the shot blocker anymore.
Imagine if you have this and the other one.
I wonder if you can get to 100% shot blocking.
That sounds insane.
Grants immunity to damage from projectiles that fall from above.
Okay, so...
We gotta try that right now.
Okay, we're trying it right now.
What I think it means is...
Like, on the screen, if the shot is coming from up here to down here, that's what it means by falling from above.
We're gonna try it, if there's enemies that shoot.
There's none in here.
Oh my god, stop!
I can't believe it.
And this one...
Ah, okay.
Oh, we also have the magician card.
Let's not forget.
Here, enjoy that one.
Oh,
yeah, I was about to say I shouldn't stand next to that.
Wait, why is there a shadow over here?
You see that?
Look on the right side.
Look at the shadow on the wall.
Something's going on here.
Nevermind.
Okay.
Well, that was a disappointment.
Alright, moving on.
Ah, should I go in here?
Nah, nope, no thanks.
I'm going this way.
Time for the boss.
Actually, things have been going decently.
Widow.
Wait, I thought this guy was called the wall.
I'm getting everything confused here.
Fuck!
Oh my god!
Okay, we got him.
Oh, bandage is good.
Oh, that's a very good one.
Very nice.
Let's go.
We bought a wig and then people laughed at us or what?
Come here.
This guy's gonna die.
Boy, that was a big bomb too.
Okay, we got to try the projectile theory now.
As soon as we can.
You know what, let's give this guy a bunch of money.
Brother.
Oh, what's that?
Two spades, double Isaac's keys.
Ah...
It's horrible.
What if I give you more money?
No!
These guys are just a scam, man.
Wow!
Okay, wait, wait!
Oh wait, fuck, let me kill this guy first.
Jesus!
Push him up, push him up a bit.
You got to push him up like this.
I took damage from shots that fall from above.
So that's not what it means.
Okay, maybe it means the shots that get thrown up in the air land and explode.
Maybe that's what that means.
Yeah.
Hey, we got some bombs.
I feel like my damage is not that good.
Wait, did I just block a shot there?
Sweet.
I love these rooms.
There's also this room.
What's that?
Sinus infection, booger tears!
Chance to fire boogers here to stick to enemies and deal.
Oh, that's good.
I like it.
That's similar to the other booger we had, but not quite the same.
Two spades.
Wait, what?
I'm confused what just happened.
Mom's footstomp's down.
The high priestess.
What was that?
Two spades again.
The keys, right.
I mean, sure.
Just give me a key.
This is the mom thing.
Plus three range.
How does homing shots work for my laser?
I guess we'll find out.
Oh, wrong button.
Goddammit.
That's not homing.
Or is it?
Let me try and miss.
Yeah, there's no homing about this.
But it's green now because of the boogers.
That guy's so confused.
Huge.
Oi!
That was bad.
Well, black hearts are gone.
Matchstick.
Tastes like burning.
Okay, so now I can actually...
Okay, here we go.
10% increased chance of finding bombs.
Nice.
33% chance to add an additional bomb to chests, tinted rocks and destroyed machines.
And then 33% chance to add an additional bomb.
Oh, that's the same.
Okay, can remove the tick...
Oh!
Cool.
Well, I want this, I guess.
I want to find the secrets.
At least I...
Okay.
Wait.
Who's the man Tonsil?
Places a decoy?
No, wait, that's not the same.
What did I get?
Oh, it's the...
Oh, it's the bottom left.
After taking damage 6 to 12 times, spawn a Tonsil familiar that blocks shots.
After a second Tonsil is spawned, the trinket is destroyed.
Okay.
I think I like that.
Let's try it.
That sounds cool.
What are the chances?
I mean, it was like at the end of a long ass room with nothing else.
It was a little suspicious.
No, I need more range.
That's the boss.
Not yet.
Man, I look like a mess.
My character's all pricked up.
Wait a minute.
Oh, no.
Okay, never mind.
Let's go this way.
Man, I keep underestimating.
Or overestimating how fast I actually charged this beam.
Like, I release it way too early.
Oh, no.
Oh, I guess I can heal now.
Show yourself.
Get poisoned.
Oi, yo, yo.
Oh, the drive-by.
Very good.
Lucky rock.
There's something inside it.
I'm getting so many of these items in the bottom left here.
Rocks and other obstacles have a chance to drop one penny when destroyed.
Really?
So if I end up in a run with like...
I don't know, like a million bombs, this would be really good.
But I'm going to stick with this, I guess.
That guy's so old brown.
I wonder what that color means.
Gray is bomb, right?
No?
Okay, he didn't explode.
Oh, I want this one!
Can we get money?
We need money.
Maybe there's a way to get money.
No, we only have the boss.
There's no way to get money.
Oh, that's too bad.
I would love to get that.
Wow.
Oh!
Chop!
The poison thing is going to be good here if it actually triggers.
Oh god.
Get poison, nerd!
There's a lot of ads now.
Oh, no way.
Oh, look at all that poison!
Insanity.
Blood clot, plus one damage in range for ice...
Oh, that's good.
We love that.
Wait, it doesn't feel like...
Does that even affect us at all?
What the hell?
That seems useless.
Man, do we not have any way of getting money here?
What about the little guy that takes coins or something?
Do we have one at...
Oh, hey, there we go.
One coin.
Let's look for suspicious rocks.
This guy, maybe we can blow him up.
Here.
Alright!
I mean, it's not money, but it's awesome.
Oh, I don't have a card.
Hey, cool.
Very good.
We have eight monies now.
I forgot what else was in the store.
Oh, no, no, no.
Oh, a battery, okay.
Should I donate?
Yeah, why not?
May as well do it.
I wonder when the next break point is.
Or something good.
And we leave.
Lovely.
Halfway through the run here.
Catacombs.
We have the high priestess, that is the foot from heaven.
There you.
The fool.
Oh, you know what, I'm gonna use that.
I think.
There you go.
That's what you got.
Oh, nice!
How good was that, huh?
Wait, how come these guys are still active?
Didn't I clear everything?
Oh, okay.
Got him.
Cool.
Oh, now they're... okay, they're still shooting.
Oh, yeah.
Uh...
Harlequin baby.
Double shot, buddy.
Familiar that fires two tiers in a split pattern.
Okay, I mean, that could come in handy, I guess.
Cool.
Hey, super lucky.
Getting some money back.
Not too shabby.
Wait, I have a feeling.
Nah, let's not waste bombs on feelings.
Not right now.
We should only be doing that if we have excess of bombs.
Oh, watch this!
We're gonna enter here.
Whoa!
Nothing?
Wait, someone here!
Oh, okay.
I thought my familiar was an enemy shooting.
So watch this.
The tactics, baby!
Come on now, that was genius.
That was actually so good.
Aha, but I can fly, motherfucker!
Yep, yep, yep.
The perks...
are immense.
God, these are so disgusting.
Uh, I need some sus rocks in here.
Okay, I have a feeling here, guys.
I have four bombs, I can go on feelings.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on.
Grants immunity to damage from projectiles that fall from above.
Okay, so let's try this.
We're gonna try and get hit by this.
Wait, does it work?
Again, again.
We're using him to open...
Dude, that's actually so smart!
What the fuck?
No freaking way!
Oh, no, what a horrible room.
I mean...
I'm gonna blow it up.
What if I blow this guy up?
Oh, wait, I gained five in...
in heaven.
Or the angel.
Why?
What was that?
What the hell was that?
Ouroboros worm.
More tears in range, tears fire in a wide spiral pattern?
Grant spectral tears.
Chance for homing tears that increases with luck.
I don't know if I like that.
Okay, actually.
That's pretty cool.
I like it.
I do like it.
Oh, it's a bottom left item.
It's a BLI.
I'm gonna cheat here and go along the bottom.
That's how you deal... Oh my god, that's actually so cool!
Okay, I love the ouroboros.
You can eat your tail all day.
Imagine getting more range with this!
Wait, am I dealing less damage now, though, because of it?
It feels like I'm not doing as much damage.
Maybe the time that the beam touches the enemy is actually reduced this way.
It seems pretty good, though.
Oh yeah, it's very good, guys!
Wait, wait!
I have a feeling!
A crazy feeling!
Imagine, though!
Imagine the secrets that could be there.
You know?
We have 15 coins.
That means we can buy this thing.
Mom's bottle of pills?
Oh no, that's an active.
Oh!
Grant!
Yes!
I want it!
Uh, space.
My god!
I'm gonna have to buy that.
Just to stay safe.
Wow!
I need more mana.
It's not going super well, guys.
Uh, this way.
Precharge the laser.
Oh yeah.
I'm not gonna gamble with more bombs.
I'm losing all my bombs with this map.
Oh wait.
I never went in here.
I did go in here, nevermind.
What if they had like a secret room in a secret room?
I still can't enter there.
What?
Okay.
What if I could enter there via the secret room?
No way!
Magic scab gives me luck?
Health?
Oh yeah!
Bring it on!
Oh, it's a boss-type enemy.
Oh god.
Oi, oi, oi!
Fuck me, fuck me, fuck me!
Alright, alright.
There's more, though.
We're not done.
Oh, it's bosses only.
We're gonna die.
Somehow we're not dead.
Jesus Christ.
Unbelievable.
Wait, do we have healing anywhere?
We have a little bit of healing, actually.
In the room below.
I'm gonna grab that immediately.
Wait, it's in here?
Oh!
Huge.
We also had some healing up here.
We're gonna generate so many pills, we're gonna become an ultimate addict this run.
Okay?
This is the pill run.
I think we're ready to face...
It's not Mom, is it?
Not yet.
No.
The husk.
I don't think I've seen that guy before.
Oh, man.
Kill the small guys.
Wow, he died for the poison!
Oh!
Huge.
Wait, I'm taking damage from something.
Okay.
Midnight snack, more health!
That's huge!
Very good.
No more toilet paper.
I love when this music starts.
It feels good in my tummy.
Okay, you wanna die?
I would love to get a bit more damage.
I feel like that's what I'm lacking right now.
Oh, they all died.
Oh.
Okay.
Wait, is that a suspicious rock?
Why is it so suspicious looking?
Hold on.
Hey, enemies!
Alright.
And the drive-by and the spiral-by.
Okay.
More skulls.
Wait, this blood is gonna damage me?
It's blinking.
I think that creep does damage to me.
Okay, we're gonna spawn a pill.
Question mark?
Tears up!
Huge!
Dude, this is gonna be so good.
Come to me.
Oi!
Okay, you do that.
Wow.
Lovely.
And I love that I hit that guy from the back as well when I use this.
Oh!
Right, you can jump over rocks.
That's the thing.
Okay.
Any suspicious rocks in here?
Not that I can see.
I could place one right here and get a large surface area going.
Ah, not a good idea.
Don't gamble.
Are you gonna explode?
It's a bomb, right?
There it is.
Whoa!
Dim bulb.
Grants an increase to all stats when held.
Active items charged is fully depleted.
Wait.
Oh, it's a bottom left item.
Um...
Wait, plus 1.5.
Oh, we don't have MT.
I see.
Our active is not MT.
I wonder how good it is, though.
I like this, though.
Oh no, oh no, oh my god, you're shooting fast.
How on earth?
Yep.
Okay.
Insanity!
I don't have enough money for that.
What is this weird room?
Um...
Get a pill?
Health down?
Absolutely not!
Um...
Oh shit, how do I not use it?
Can I drop it?
I don't wanna accidentally use it.
Meanwhile I'm dying here.
Oh, this is a boss enemy.
I thought I was like, how does he have so much HP?
That makes sense.
I guess I can use the active again and it will replace the pill, I guess.
Dude, I have a feeling right here.
Shit!
Okay, I'm gonna stop with the feelings.
No more feelings.
We're done with that.
Wow.
Yeah, you can't reach me now, can you, noobs?
Wow!
What are you gonna do?
What are you gonna do when I come for you?
Oh, that was a spiky one.
What's this?
Hookworm.
Tears travel in a square wave-like pattern?
Say what?
Ah, that doesn't sound good at all.
Hello.
Bo...
Ah, this one's good.
That is a cake, isn't it?
Don't tell me it's poop.
It's a fruit cake!
Rainbow effects!
Love it!
Every tear fired has a random effect.
Oh, okay.
Oh!
That is indeed a random effect.
Huh?
Alright, this is gonna be interesting.
Very weird.
Oh, shit, shit.
No way.
How lucky am I?
I'm actually dying.
I'm gonna go back and pick up that health.
I'm playing it safe.
Play it safe.
Got it.
Why?
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Why did I go back?
No, I went back for the health of... Wait, there's more?
Why is there still a health icon here?
Oh, it's just not updated, I see.
Was there anything else in here?
Oh, yeah, right, this... true.
Uh, you know what?
Let me try blowing this up.
It gave... okay, it gave me ten on the... on the... I was about to say star.
On the angel.
What the fuck is going on with my tears?
It's a mess.
Absolute mess.
Also, I'm kinda rich.
Maybe we should go back to the store.
See what we can purchase.
Oh, yeah, right.
There's nothing in there.
Weird.
I wonder why that is.
Why is it empty?
Is there a random chance of that happening, perhaps?
Oh, my God.
Bro, I... all this shit on my screen that's floating around, I don't understand what's happening.
This guy's frozen.
Oh, God.
Now, check it out.
This room we cannot enter, right?
I don't mind, I don't have any bombs.
I was about to be a smartass.
Unfortunately, I can't.
I can't be a smartass.
If I... if I consume this pill, I die.
So, I'm not gonna do it.
Uh, I don't even know where to go.
It's time for the boss.
Oh!
Nice!
That was kinda huge.
Oh, no.
I want this.
Maybe... do I want this?
Hold on.
What was that?
I need to see if this is better.
Grants an increase to all stats when held active's item charge is fully depleted.
I mean, that's not really that often, because most of the time it's not gonna be fully de... fully depleted, right?
In fact, that's gonna be super rare.
And I'm assuming I can't just not have an active.
Okay, here we go.
Loki.
I forgot what you do.
Oh, no, not these weird things moving around.
Oh, wow.
Okay, there's bombs.
Okay, thank God.
Why they're still... Oh, I see, I see.
Oh, this is, uh, Mr. Dolly?
More range?
That's big.
Oh, yeah.
Cool.
All right.
It's looking pretty good.
Only, uh, two more... three more levels.
And it's mom time.
Also, we're gonna eat a pill.
It's a new one.
I found pills and ate them.
What does that do?
I didn't notice what just happened.
Okay, whatever.
Hey!
Whoa!
Holy shit.
Uh, we can blow this up, I guess.
Oh, yeah, we have a bomb.
Oh, what's that?
More lock and a soul heart.
And more keys.
Massive.
We're gonna wait with that room.
Actually, destroy these.
This run is amazing.
It is incredible.
Look at all that money!
What the heck, man?
More bombs and keys.
Oh, uh, we can definitely go in here.
So this room has a little treasure chest on it.
Okay, so is it always gonna be just the money room?
Let's try blowing this guy up.
Ah, we have two bombs.
Should I do it?
I'm gonna wait.
Kinda low on bombs.
Maybe I'll come back later for that, yeah.
I'll come back later.
Oh.
Okay, so we can't go in there down there, but maybe there's a way around.
We can blow a hole in a wall somewhere.
That could be the play.
Charge it up.
Whoa.
Jesus Christ.
Okay.
More bombs, that's good.
Whoa!
That was a random effect, I guess.
Wait, I have a feeling here, guys.
Nah, we're not gonna act on feelings.
We're done with that.
Okay, there we go.
And not the health down!
What is it with these pills?
Let me have another one.
No!
I'm getting all the shitty pills.
Unbelievable.
I feel like this active item is a bait.
There's probably a higher chance of spawning shitty pills with it.
Wait, how did you hit me?
Huh?
Did you see that?
This guy got destroyed.
That's highly unusual.
What is that?
Mom's contacts.
Breeze effect.
More range, chance to fire petrifying tears.
How's that gonna work with all the other random effects that's happening?
Is that being overwritten, or...
I have no idea.
There's like so many questions I have about this sort of technicality, you know?
Wow!
Dude, I am rich AF!
Let's have a store!
Two spades, doubles, I6 keys.
Oh!
Holy shit, that's good!
16 keys!
We're gonna blow this up.
Okay.
I don't really need money anymore.
Whoa, sick room!
Bombs are more valuable to me.
Oh, we got pills!
Uh...
Hema... team is this?
Oh, I lost HP!
Oh, no.
One makes you smaller...
Oh, this one makes me smaller, okay, okay.
We're gonna blow this up.
Hey!
Sweet!
The boss is here.
We're not gonna engage.
Man, that guy was going crazy.
Key for me.
Here we go, a shop!
Ooh, what's that?
This is the one I wanted to buy once.
I'm gonna predict that this one will allow me to...
Let's think, it's like a pouch, right?
It will allow me to hold more things.
Which things, though?
Maybe I can have two active items, or maybe two...
BLIs at the same time.
Filled with goodies.
Fanny pack.
50% chance to drop a pickup.
Okay, nevermind.
That was completely off.
But that's also pretty cool.
We're gonna donate all our money.
Ah, I broke.
Dang.
Oh, well.
At least we donated a bunch.
And we can use a pill.
Lock up!
Ooh!
Dude, we're so lucky!
Three?
Unlock!
I wonder what's gonna happen with all that.
Let's actually...
We're gonna go up here.
There's another room.
Whoa!
Thought I saw a suspicious rock.
I didn't.
Wait, it decreases max health by one heart.
Turns into a health up pill.
If Isaac has one heart or fewer.
Oh!
That's good to know!
Very cool!
I didn't know that.
Ah, this one is also the same.
Oh, fuck.
I'm an idiot.
Wait, what?
What just happened?
Alright, good enough.
More pills!
Oh, massive!
Four a lock, baby!
What does it mean?
This door's not open.
Dang!
Where am I going?
We can also go grab a bunch of HP on the way.
There was a room with a bunch of HP.
Come on down here.
Wait, what's going on with these skulls?
Let me throw a bomb here, so it also has a chance to destroy the wall.
Oh!
Turns into an enemy.
Wait, look!
There's an axe on the floor!
Come on.
Okay, I'm full HP.
Alright, here we go, here we go.
Last time.
It's Mom!
Already?
Huh.
Oi, that was bad, that was bad.
What's that, what's that?
What the hell was that?
Okay, not too bad.
Mom's underwear.
This will take us to three out of three?
Yes, Mother?
Oh, oh, we have the knife again!
What is the point of the knife?
I don't understand.
Can I somehow use it?
Ooh!
Jesus juice.
That's just good.
There's no other way to put it.
Yo, what if I blow this guy up?
Should we be ungrateful?
No, I have one.
Oh, I'm taking damage!
What the hell?
Hell no.
We're going.
Let's go, let's go.
Oh, oh wait, so Mom happens on eight.
Oh, one, two, three, four, on six.
Okay, I see how it works now.
I thought Mom was the last one in the sequence, and then we got to a new sort of stage-ish.
Wait, how?
Oh, he's down there, I see.
There we go.
This way?
That was a very bad room.
It was horrible.
Okay,
one of them is down.
Oh shit, oh my god.
This was horrible.
Like, there's so much stuff on my screen.
I legit have trouble understanding what's going on, because there's so much stuff.
Also, I'm not liking my freaking spiral anymore.
Spiral bad.
I want my old one back.
As soon as I find another BLI, I'm going to use it.
Jesus.
We can have a pill.
Question mark.
W pill!
Oh, you know what?
Let's try something crazy.
I'm going to put a bomb right in the center.
Wait, what?
Did I just make a bridge with that?
Oh, look at this, I...
I just made a bridge with that!
Cool.
I mean, that was not my intention.
I was going to see if there was a secret somewhere.
Oh my god.
But I can fly anyways, who cares?
Haha!
That's funny.
Doubles Isaac's...
Oh no, please give me that when I have more bombs.
I don't need it yet.
Oh, what the hell?
I've never seen that guy.
What was that?
Why did that blow up?
Maybe the spiral is okay.
It's just a little bit random.
And the way it does things...
What's this going to be?
No!
Okay.
Well, at least we're learning.
What the pills do.
Yeah, okay.
I do like the spiral.
May the light heal and enlighten you.
Oh, we don't know what it does.
But I guess it heals and enlightens me.
Whatever enlightenment means.
Is the room done?
No, not yet.
There we go.
Ah, wait, that's my last bomb.
Hold on.
I need to see something first.
Maybe I can get more bombs so I can double it.
There we go.
Look at that.
Do you see the play?
You saw the play?
Oh, I'm going to spawn a pill.
This one is a question mark.
Man, there are so many different pills.
Lockdown?
No.
Ooh.
I guess I was a little too lucky, huh?
Oh, my God.
Oh, it's good against these.
Oh, yeah, I like the spiral there.
The high priestess.
I remember that one.
Is that the one with the foot?
Yeah, mom's foot stomps down.
The sun deals 100 damage to all enemies.
Fully heals Isaac, reveals the map, and rem...
What?
Whoa!
Wow, that is crazy.
This card is insanity.
So good.
Oh, give me that.
Oh, wait.
What's happening?
Oh, I didn't even see the spiders.
Blind as hell.
What's that?
Isaac's fork!
10% chance to heal half a red heart each time you clear a room.
Oh, well, that's gonna be often, then.
Because I have a lot of...
Okay, let me see here.
No, I want this.
It's like the range is better with it, too.
Somehow.
I missed everything with that shot.
Okay.
Nice, we got another bomb.
Now we can go duplicate.
I'm gonna clear one more room.
Little tiny hearts.
What is... what are they doing?
Purple heart.
Nice, I got wounded in combat, then.
Increases chance of encountering champion enemies and bosses?
50% chance for champions to drop their special loot.
Loot dropped from champions is doubled.
Oh, man.
Oh, shit, should I be using this?
That sounds really cool, actually.
Maybe I'll replace it back with the Ouroboros later.
Let's just gamble our hearts out here with all this money.
Let's go crazy.
Wow, this is just a scam.
A straight-up scam.
But maybe if you put enough coins in there and then blow it up, you get even something better, you know?
Maybe that's...
Oh, hey, there we go.
Very good.
Money for me.
I do wonder what else I can win with this.
Oh, oh no.
Aww.
That's the end of that.
Got it.
Okay.
Oh, buttons, I see.
Wow.
Where are my champion-type enemies?
What is that guy even?
Wait, I have a feeling.
Be jackpot, baby!
Oh, oh, oh, wait.
Okay.
Well, that's not gonna help me anymore.
That's kind of bad.
You want bombs?
I can go duplicate bombs first.
But hold on.
Oh, you got frozen, didn't you?
That's the boss.
Okay, so we found the boss.
Let's go back and finally do the...
Dude, am I gonna...
No, no, not yet.
One down and then right.
I'm actually so excited!
Oh!
Here we go.
This way.
I'm gonna pick that up in a second.
There's also another room with the moon and the plus sign.
Was it this one?
No, that's the mom's foot.
Wait, where did I leave it?
All the way back here.
Here it is.
Double it.
Nice!
And we can grab this.
We also have a...
What is this one?
Oh, yeah, right.
Nice!
Wow.
So many bombs.
We should bomb every wall now.
Honestly?
Because the boss down there is actually gonna be mom's heart, I think.
I could be wrong on that.
Hey!
Well, there you go.
Let me bomb some walls.
Okay.
Hey!
A win!
Uh-oh!
Is that a champion-type enemy?
I'm about to fuck him up.
What's that?
Oh!
Oh, okay.
We're gonna keep bombing.
Wait, what?
Oh, there's three axis paths.
Nothing, okay.
Where should I bomb?
I kind of feel like if I was gonna hide secrets, I would do it at the very edges, you know?
Where it's super hard to get to.
So maybe like out here in the extremities.
Actually, let's try this one.
Right here, baby.
Ah!
Boo!
You know why?
It's because I don't have a feeling.
Let me see if I have a feeling.
I go in here.
I have a feeling right here.
Shit!
Ah!
Okay, it's pills time!
Give me luck!
Man, I really hope it is actually Mom's heart now, otherwise I've been wasting all these bombs.
Uh, this way.
Let me try and bomb all the way down here.
Boi!
That was close.
What was this?
Chance Inc.
No.
Give me that one back.
Blow this up.
Shit.
Wait, can I... I wonder if I can somehow see which stage I'm in.
Like how many more stages are left.
Maybe I cannot see that.
Uh, blow this one up.
Alright.
I think, uh, I'm gonna save my last bomb in case I see something crazy.
Time for the boss.
Oh, you...
Oh, this guy wanted bombs!
Why didn't I do that?
I'll fuck you then.
Oh no, it's not even Mom's heart!
I miscalculated!
It's very bad.
But it's okay.
That is so weird.
I take too much damage.
Thank God I can heal again.
More health!
Whoa!
Huge.
Huge, huge, huge.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Before I move on.
There was a bit of healing back here.
This might seem pedantic, but...
I need it.
Now jump inside the nice looking hole there.
This is the end stage.
Whatever we do now, we'll echo through the ages.
Nice.
I do wish I didn't use all my...
bombs.
That's okay.
What the hell was that?
He did nothing.
Charge it up.
Oh yeah, huge.
Wow!
I have a pretty good setup going here, guys.
I think we can do it.
Can I just turn that guy into poop?
Oh yeah, look at that!
Fantastic stuff.
I could donate health, but I could also not.
Wait, what?
Oh.
Oh, too bad for you, isn't it?
Got frozen there.
Pill time.
Tears up!
Huge.
Wait, what?
Did I just destroy a rock?
Oh, maybe one of the random effects I have on my attack is that it becomes like a bomb.
So if I keep doing this, could I potentially...
find secrets like this?
Hold on.
I need to experiment.
Purple?
Electricity or something?
Okay, I'm not sure what happened there.
Okay, we're obviously not going to go in there yet.
We're going to explore everything to get as powerful as possible.
Oh, shit.
Oh, crash balls!
Hit that button!
Okay, good.
Whoa!
Wait, what?
You see something exploded just now?
How did that work?
Another machine.
I don't want to donate.
I want to keep my blood.
Thank you very much.
Wow, the purple laser.
We got a question mark pill.
Telepills!
Oh, thanks.
Good looking out, fam.
Alright.
Man, that's a lot of money.
What the hell?
Oh, a bomb.
That guy just blew up.
Oh, wait, it's not the stones.
It's like the weird looking stones that blow up.
I see how it is.
They're not actually pure stones.
Wait, this is definitely a secret.
No way.
Okay, fine.
Ah, here we go.
Oh, we have so many coins!
Wait, this is the shell game guy.
Also, I have pills.
One makes you smaller.
I like that.
Wait, what?
We actually won?
Huh?
What happened?
Okay, so you can't do that.
Oh, I see.
I'm just choosing.
I see.
That's what that sound is.
I thought I was breaking the rules by talking to him in the middle of it.
Or something.
Oh, no.
Oh, you know what?
I'm going to come back later here.
Because this is obviously a way to get a bunch of HP.
I'm going to go in here now.
Hey, sweetness!
I'll take that.
Wait a minute.
Watch this.
Ho!
You see?
Some of these random effects blow certain rocks up.
Yeah?
Dang.
Oh, that was my last bomb.
That was a mistake.
Absolutely a bad idea.
Arcade!
We are rich as fuck, though!
You want money?
Money for everyone.
Wait.
Wait a minute.
There's a difference between these two.
This guy has, like, a badass haircut.
Is it, like, bad and good?
This guy looks evil and unwashed, unkempt.
I'm looking at my demon and angel meters.
Ooh, okay!
Wait, what?
The Bean!
Two... Wait, what was that?
Release a fart that poisons enemies and deflects projectiles in close range.
Compared to what?
Oh, Mom's bottle of pills.
I mean, maybe I'll come back for that.
Are you just going to keep eating my money or what?
Here you go.
Wait, are we gaining a battery?
Is that a battery symbol?
Hey!
Infinite pills?
Full health?
Oh, I mean, okay.
I want another pill.
Wait, I could have saved that for the boss, actually.
That would have been smart.
I'm just going to keep giving him money.
Oh, what's that?
4.5 volt.
Dealing damage to enemies gradually recharges active items.
At a rate of 1 charge bar per 60 damage dealt.
That could be good with the Bean!
Active items no longer gain charges from room clears.
That's perfect, because I'm not going to clear any more rooms!
Oh!
Yeah?
Not bad?
We grab the Bean?
Wait, unless we can still pump out a pill.
There's still a couple rooms that need clearing.
I'll be back.
There's also a card over here that I left behind.
I need to see what that is.
Oh, that one!
That's a good one!
I need to keep that.
Very good card.
I got one bomb left.
There's also a room up here that we couldn't have accessed, but maybe we can now.
No, we can't.
Damn.
Wait a minute, I have a big brain strategy.
Huge idea.
Watch this, we're going to blow this up, get two bombs.
Fuck!
Damn.
Okay.
I think it's time.
Ah, so I'm going to go grab the Bean.
Oh wait, there's also one in here.
Ah, but I can't blow it up, though.
That's the problem.
This way.
Wait, we also had these two, I guess.
Oh wait, wait, we can gamble!
Let's gamble the hell out of this.
Oh!
Portable slot, no.
Wait, we could do that.
Why not?
Why shouldn't I gamble?
Pills!
Full health, nice!
But is it better than the sun, though?
The sun is even better, because this one also heals me fully.
Right?
I'm going to keep gambling.
I gained a fly.
Keep gambling.
Another pill?
I found pills?
This is the one with no effect?
It has no effect!
Why do I not believe that?
Keep gambling.
Gamble down here.
I wonder what else I can get from gambling.
Hey!
Huge!
Uh...
Wait, hematemesis?
Wait, wait!
I can read about it.
Sets Isaac's health to one red heart, spawns one to four red hearts.
No, that's bad.
We don't want that.
So that's what hematemesis does.
More luck?
Sure, why not?
Keep gambling.
A pill?
Another full health.
So many full health pills.
Maybe gambling has a higher chance of spawning one of those types of pills.
Another fly!
We're almost out of money.
That's it, we got it all.
So let's grab this guy.
And we're leaving.
Interestingly, I didn't get any bombs at all from that.
So maybe you cannot gain bombs from gambling.
At least not the portable gambler.
Okay, so let's think about this.
Oh wait, I need to grab the bean.
I'm not going to gamble anymore anyway.
What happens if I try?
Oh, I got no money.
Let's grab the bean.
Oh, there it is.
Toot on co...
What was that again?
Deflect projectiles.
That's actually huge.
Especially against this boss we're about to face.
It is massive.
And we can recharge quickly and just spam it, I guess.
As soon as add spawn, I'm going to use the sun.
No, no.
As soon as I'm low HP, I'm going to use the sun.
This is the plan.
Let's go, baby.
No problem.
Oh, look at the black hole.
Part those projectiles away.
Bro, I'm fucking owning this.
Didn't even lose a single heart of HP.
Freaking nailed it.
Not even close.
Holy shit.
Let's see that bot.
I want to see that bot of yours.
There it is.
Look at it.
It's a noose.
That's not good.
Huh?
Well, I guess he did have a shitty childhood.
I totally get it.
That sucks, man.
Why would he...
After a win like that, I guess, you know what?
He probably thought, you know what?
I peeked.
I can't do anything better than this, so I may as well take myself out.
Alright, that was a good warm up.
You unlocked Solar System.
Very nice.
Fantastic warm up.
Let's try a new character.
Let's try Cain.
Luckfoot.
I wonder if that simply means I have more luck to start with.
Let's see.
I start with one luck.
So maybe that is what's happening.
Two HP.
Okay.
Let's do this.
Oh, why do you shoot things?
Gotta be careful.
Man, it's so weird shooting projectiles again.
When you're used to Azazel.
Look at his fart face.
Oh my god, stop.
This guy is fucking tactical.
He's hiding in the corner.
I can't win.
It's over.
How do I get close to him?
Alright, alright, he's coming this way.
Look at him dodging.
I'm dead.
Fuck me.
It's over.
Okay, we got him, we got him.
Whoo!
Oi, oi, oi.
Fucking hell, my heart rate.
Oh, how I wish I could fly.
How I wish I could fly.
Uh oh, this guy blows up.
We gotta be careful.
What's that?
Okay, that's good though.
Man, I wish I could fly.
I swear to god, like every other character is so bad compared to Azazel.
Being able to fly in itself is unbelievably good, you know?
I think it's most definitely over.
Jesus.
This is a crazy room.
I'm not hitting anything, it's crazy.
There we go.
Got some good hits in there.
Wait, there's like a basement thing here.
Oh, nice healing.
Wait, there's some healing I missed.
I need it.
Oh, but I can't get to it.
Shit.
Okay, fine.
I'm gonna go down in the basement.
Oh, oh, it's this stuff!
Okay.
Folk of shadows, gain a damage null.
Okay, that's good.
I like that one.
Oh, I could go in there.
But then I can't go out again.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Does this last cross rooms?
If I use this...
I have to remember what's going on in there.
This is just like a chest or something, right?
Ooh.
Let's go in here first.
Play-Doh cookie!
Each tier Isaac fires, gains a random color.
Okay, bonus add?
Yeah, okay.
So there's all kinds of random shit.
So random bullshit go, pretty much.
What if I go back down?
What if there's a secret down here?
What if I blow up, like, some of these walls here?
I don't have any bombs, though.
It is something to think about, though.
Now, what is that symbol that is all the way up here?
Oh, chest.
Okay.
If I get a bomb, I can get in there.
And there's a chest here.
Wow.
What is that one?
I can't even tell what I'm looking at.
Tarot card.
All right.
I have a feeling it's not going to go so well.
Yeah, this guy is tough as hell.
I'm going to die here, for sure.
Oh, I just got to keep moving, I guess.
So I jumped three times in a row.
Oh, God.
Oh,
what a horrible run.
Absolutely disgusting.
Well, we're going to try that again.
I mean, this character just feels like Isaac.
I mean, what am I missing here?
What is this?
I have some kind of lock foot.
How come I can't read about that?
Like, I don't know what it does.
How am I supposed to know?
Maybe it is just one lock.
I don't remember if Isaac starts with one lock or not.
Okay, we obviously go in here.
Wait, wait, so this is a choice.
I can't pick both.
Oh, this one sucks ass.
I want this glowing hourglass.
Turn back time?
Rewinds time and places Isaac in the previous room on doing everything that occurred in the room.
After three uses, instead uses the hourglass effect.
Three sets uses each floor.
Instead uses the hourglass effect?
What is the hourglass effect?
I like that it says that as if I know it.
Oh, I can take both.
Really?
Huh.
Okay, I thought that was a choice.
Well, uh, cool.
We got bombs.
I'm looking for suspicious rocks.
Oh, they're gonna blow up, they're gonna blow up.
Beautiful.
Ah, come on.
What the fuck, man?
It spawns right on top of me.
I guess I could undo what happened in here.
I'm undoing it.
Oh, wait, the enemies are also undone!
Okay, well, in that case, then it's a little less good.
It's still good, though.
I can undo mistakes.
I thought it would just be like the state of Isaac.
You're nothing else, you know?
A Christmas present.
I'm gonna blow this guy up.
It didn't affect my, uh, statuses.
Weirdly.
Oh, a pill, I would love to get that.
Uh, yeah, worth.
Nice!
So, experimental pill, I think that one is just random forever.
You don't know what you're gonna get, it's just, you know, whatever.
Because I seem to remember getting damage up with that once.
And now I got something else.
Oh, what an interesting room here.
Eh, I'm not gonna go in there.
Ah, we do have that.
Oh, we can undo.
But do I get to keep items if I undo?
I, hold on, what does it say?
Reminds time and places Isaac on doing everything that occurred.
I mean, that, to me, sounds like it includes stuff like this down here, you know?
Then again, walking in there, is that considered something that happened in the room or not?
I'm not gonna take the chance.
Yeah, we're just gonna go to the boss.
It's the hot.
Here we go.
Oh, my rage is really bad.
Oh, come on.
Wait, can I use this?
Oh, no!
Okay.
I can't use my...
Okay, I can.
I have undone.
Let's try again.
I mean, I may as well do it, right?
It resets once per floor?
Oh, my God!
These guys are predicting my movements!
All right, let's try it again, brother.
Okay.
Playing it super safe.
Ah, motherfucker!
Okay.
We got a snack.
That's huge.
All right.
I could go back now and experiment with my...
You know what?
Let's do some experiments.
That's how you learn, right?
Let's see if this counts.
Go in here.
We're gonna take damage upon entering, but I wonder if that's gonna count.
So we're gonna do this, get some pills, range up.
Whoa!
I don't think I wanna undo shit!
We're good!
No undoing here.
But I do wonder if I go back in, if it's gonna spawn different pills.
That's something we need to experiment with.
Moving on.
We got a master key thingy!
So something opened somewhere.
I don't understand...
Should I use it on this?
Oh, man.
Pathetic enemies here.
He has bodyguards.
Wait!
The door just got unlocked!
Is that what happens when you have this?
It just automatically unlocks the door when you defeat the enemies?
Ooh, that sounds nice.
A pill?
Yeah.
No!
God damn it.
How sad is that?
Arcade, we have no money, so arcade is not gonna be very much fun.
These guys are so annoying!
Okay.
I'm actually gonna go back.
I'm gonna experiment real quick.
So now I take damage.
I open this.
I take these.
Now I'm gonna undo.
Okay.
Oh!
So I also undo the damage I took upon entering!
Interesting!
Let's see if there's different stuff in the chest now.
There's not!
Okay!
So at least that's consistent.
Unless I just got super lucky or unlucky, however you wanna put that, you know?
Oh, how the...
Oh, yeah.
If I can fly, I could get in there, but I can't.
If my grandma was a bike and all that.
This one again.
The hell?
Random effects.
We got a golden poop.
Love seeing the golden poop.
It's just money, right?
Oh, that's a lot.
We're doing good on bombs and keys and everything.
We're gonna be able to open a lot of chests.
Unless this also unlocks the chests.
We could go to the arcade...
Nah, there's nothing at the arcade, just there.
There may be another room behind it, though.
Let's go back just for that.
Did that just use a key?
I didn't pay attention.
This guy's gonna scam me, right?
Like, this is very bad.
It's not good.
I'm gonna fuck him up.
That was totally worth it!
We're gonna blow up this shit.
Lovely tick.
Nah, I didn't mean to pick that one up.
Blow this one up.
Hell yeah!
Sweetness.
And now it's time for the boss.
Man, this is going pretty well so far.
Good start.
Kane Gaming.
He's gonna bring the pain.
Engage!
The poop!
Dingle!
He's charmed.
But somehow he's still after me.
Nice try.
Wait, you're gonna do that stuff, that's right.
Chilling.
Oh wait, you didn't whistle!
How come he didn't whistle?
Freaking liar.
Okay, there we go.
Super good.
Pageant boy.
Random coins and one random penny-trinket.
Ultimate Grand Supreme.
What is that coin?
Rotten penny.
Smalls a blue fly when picking up coins.
That's good, isn't it?
Blue flies are good.
Oh, we have a demon room.
Ooh, we gotta take that, we gotta take it.
The mark.
Damage plus speed up.
We also gain demon lost angel.
Plus one black heart.
Ooh, that's a lot of extra damage.
Very nice.
Huh?
Jesus Christ, that scared the crap out of me.
What the fuck is that?
I thought I would get stomped or something when that thing came down, but okay, sure.
Guess I'm moving.
Yo, what if I click the reverse button now?
No, no, it's gonna revert whatever I just entered, right?
Yeah, the boss is still defeated.
Okay, I just had to double-check.
We gain charges anyway, it's fine.
Okay, so notice how the timer is on the next floor.
So there's something going on on the next floor regarding time.
I'm gonna try and be super fast on the next floor then.
Oh god.
I like the little flaming tier, that looks super cool when it happens.
It's Envy.
Cain versus Envy.
Oh, he splits.
Whoa!
Look at this!
It's like that fire creature from Minecraft.
Oh, it's getting messy.
Come on.
Nice!
We're gonna spawn flies when we pick up those coins.
Oh no, no thanks.
These little flies are so annoying.
Uh, the high priestess?
Mom's foot?
Uh, this is the challenge room.
I'm not gonna pick up the blue heart yet.
I'm being smart about this.
Oh my god.
Why is it not being... Okay, there we go.
Wait, I think he explodes on his own after a while, when he's frozen.
Ooh!
Next room.
There's a blue guy in here.
Aye, aye.
He's stuck in a corner.
Run!
Get out of there.
Play strategic.
Strategic.
That even slows the projectiles when they are frozen.
Wait, do I have homing?
Are my projectiles...
Slightly...
Maybe just a random effect that gets applied and some of them are homing.
Because we have that item, right, that does that.
Hence the colors.
I'm trying to predict this movement, it's not easy.
He's charmed.
Huge!
Okay, so let's wait, see if he explodes on his own.
He doesn't!
Ha!
Okay.
Got it.
Are we gonna get so many flies?
I actually kind of forget what these blue flies do.
Oh, that... Oh, I guess he blew up the bomb.
Oh, come
on!
Got him.
What's that?
The common cold poison damage.
That sounds very nice.
I mean, honestly, with all these other random-ass things happening...
Does it matter?
Uh-oh.
Eh, no problem.
Guys, I have a feeling right here!
I meant here.
That's what I meant.
Actually, I didn't have a feeling.
I was...
Yeah.
Okay, moving on.
I had a lot of bombs, it's okay.
Oh, God.
How can I possibly avoid this?
I'm taking so much damage!
Wake up!
Oh, my God.
There we go.
Okay, I'm rich so we can buy everything.
What is that?
Mom's box?
This is part of the Yes Mother collection.
Spawns a trinket.
Doubles the effects of...
Wait, is the trinket the one in the bottom left?
Is that the BLI?
Oh, my God, it is.
Um... hmm.
The hourglass is pretty good, I guess.
Why didn't I reverse time in that room?
I took a lot of damage and that was stupid.
I should have done that.
Why is this red?
Red, C, and the others are white.
Why is that?
The Emperor, we know what that is.
That is, I think, range.
And maybe some damage.
Something like that.
I think I like that more.
Bombs have a 10% chance to spawn a...
No, that sucks.
We're keeping the coin.
I'm not gonna reverse time.
Not yet.
We have some healing here, too.
And a couple rooms.
Actually, this run is not that bad.
I have a good feeling about this.
Nice!
More range!
Huge!
The Emperor challenged me.
Wait, challenged me?
Is that the one that takes me to the boss room?
Let's try.
Okay, it is.
We can still use the hourglass, I guess, if shit goes wrong in here.
Oh yeah, he fukes a lot.
Yeah, some of my shots are definitely homing.
How do I know when he's gonna puke?
Oh, I can't stand in the red stuff!
Here comes the puke.
He's gonna puke again.
He's charmed.
He likes my style.
Wow.
There we go!
That wasn't too bad.
Booster pack, random cards.
That's always cool.
Oh, that's a good one.
The sun is nice.
Doubles, Icyx, bombs, oh, massive!
The Emperor teleports to the boss room.
The Devil plus two damage for the room.
Teleports to the secret room.
Ooh, I like that one!
Hell yeah!
Awesome!
Let's blow this guy up.
Oh, wait.
No.
It's not even in range.
Okay, I'm gonna fuck you up.
Oh, ho, ho, ho!
Oh.
Man, that is just horrible.
Alright, fine.
Mom's box.
I guess we could...
Do we have mana on it?
We don't have mana on it, okay.
In that case...
What if I blow you up?
Thanks.
No!
I didn't mean to buy that shit.
Oh, well.
It's okay.
We're moving on.
Actually, we're not moving on.
I have an idea.
I'm gonna see how genius it is.
Actually, I've done it before, it's not that smart.
I'm gonna go in here.
See what we get?
Okay, that's bullshit.
That's good, potentially?
Nice!
And...
Holy shit!
And then we use the card to get out.
Look at me.
Fantastic!
Now we grab the sun and we're chilling.
Boom, baby!
Boom, boom, boom, boom!
Look at me eating candy, just like I'm eating pills.
Except, instead of candy, it's actually good for me.
Nah, nah, nah, nah, nah, not good.
Oh!
Ultra pride!
Is that an enhanced enemy?
Or like, what was it called, champion?
Oh shit.
Yeah, some of my shots are definitely honing in.
Oh no.
The left hand.
I don't know if I want this.
I feel like red chests are...
Okay, let's think about it like this.
If you're low on keys, this could be good.
Right?
That's how you should think about it.
Because some of the golden chests you cannot even access if you don't have keys.
Huh?
But let's leave it until we see the whole stage.
I want to see if we find more keys.
Oh, these guys are tough.
How did they die?
I think I put a dot on them.
Man, I'm getting good at shooting at distance, huh?
Man, that was clean.
Super clean.
Oh no.
This is not very clean!
Alright, reverse!
Run it back!
Try again.
Nice, that's a better start.
Ah, fuck me!
Nice.
No!
Run it back!
Try again.
Get pumped, nerds!
Run it back!
We're not gonna do that room.
Moving on.
That room sucks ass.
Run into my shots, yes!
Run into my shots!
That's good, that's good.
No, no, no, come here!
Bro, where are you going?
Lovely.
Wait, the hourglass...
Wait, hold on a minute.
Hold on, so...
Oh yeah, there was something about it turning into another type of hourglass.
I need to remember what that does.
We need a bit more mana for that.
Lots of lives for me!
What a dodge!
Incredible.
Arcade, we are rich!
You want keys?
No, you want exactly the stuff I don't have.
You know what I'm gonna do?
Good night.
Load that up, we're gonna blow this up.
Money!
Hahaha, not bad, huh?
I'm making all the right decisions right now, it's actually crazy.
What's that?
The moon.
Ooh, we like the moon!
Secret room!
This thing's gonna attack me!
I'm not gonna fall for his shenanigans again.
Wait, what is the point of this room?
I'm gonna blow him up.
No.
Wait, we gained the demon points.
Let's do it again.
Okay, it just spawns little baby spiders.
Wait...
Haha!
Yeah!
Beautiful performance.
No!
What a waste.
That's fine.
We're totally chilling.
Let's see what this does.
I guess it slows down enemies.
Oh, you're frozen, aren't you?
Can't do nothing now.
Come here, you.
There we go.
He's just frozen forever until I decide to take him out of it.
Actually kind of cool.
He's gonna blow up.
Nice item.
That is going...
I don't know what that is gonna be.
Leo...
Stop.
What a beard!
What is that called?
Like, lions have.
They have like a mange.
Isaac can break most obstacles by walking over them!
Whoa!
Wait, there's pills in the rocks?
Holy shit!
It's 100 babies!
Or however that goes.
Kenya!
That's an old one.
We're gonna walk over so many things.
Wait, I just walked on it!
Can I walk?
Ah, walking over enemies would be too easy, right?
I'm not even gonna try it, because it's so silly.
Okay.
And we can slow time down as well.
This is amazing!
I wanna explore everything.
Now that we can walk over everything.
Oh wait, that's a boss down there.
You know what?
It's time.
I have the capabilities.
We have the technology.
To finally face this room.
Here we go!
Time has slowed, ladies and gentlemen!
Oh my god!
Boom!
Fire!
Kenya!
Who's the man?
That's right!
Your days are numbered.
Ah, this one is still closed.
Man, I wonder how that works.
When can I go in there?
Let's go to the shop, and then boss.
We also left the cart behind.
That's a good one.
This is the portal.
Unidentified, we take it.
I found pills.
So nothing special there.
Let's try this.
Let me blow you up.
No money for me!
Wow, nothing.
Do I want this one?
No, I think I'll keep my hourglass.
It's actually pretty good.
Well, that's a new one!
Mega maw!
Whoa!
No, wait, I've seen you before.
That's not new.
The extra range here really helps.
Look at me just standing here.
I'm barely doing anything.
And the little guys are not even running towards me.
I mean, come on now.
What kind of boss is that even?
What's that?
A wooden spoon, speed up.
Why does the spoon give me speed up?
I don't understand these logical things.
The belt speeds you up.
The freaking spoon speeds you up.
How about running shoes?
Is that going to slow you down?
Okay, let's go.
This one is a mom.
No, next one is a mom.
Next one is mom.
Uh, what?
I'm eating rocks.
What am I supposed to do?
What's the point of this room?
Uh, maybe nothing?
Just move on.
Whoa.
Oh, I can break the skull.
I can break all these things.
Eat all the rocks.
Man, that guy's brain is just hanging there.
You see that?
I wonder why that is.
That's one heavy brain.
Ooh, can I?
I cannot walk over that, though.
Stabler?
More damage?
Stable's left eye shot.
Causing all shots to...
Is that good, though?
Wait, I already have one eye shot.
Wait.
Stable's left eye shot.
Okay, so it's already sort of...
It's fine.
There's no difference, right?
Okay.
I think we're good.
Wait, I think these small ones are gonna spawn a lot of shit.
Oh, no, never mind.
These are not the ones.
Some enemies spawn like a million flies when they die.
I don't remember which ones, but they look like these, I think.
This way.
Whoa!
New enemy!
Okay, wasn't that hard.
Kill a tomato.
I wonder if I can destroy these.
I can't.
I can't!
Get out of there!
Why is the map open?
I'm so confused.
I'm throwing.
The run is over.
This is the hardest room of all time.
Um...
I should have reversed time!
Fuck, I forgot I had it.
No, dude.
Wait, his brain popped out.
What the?
Wait, reverse!
Run it back.
Try again.
Wait, is it different?
Aww, we lost HP again.
It was already a waste then.
Man, what?
Well, okay.
I'm gonna say it now.
Cain sucks.
I hate Cain.
Absolutely hate him.
He sucks ass.
I don't even know what Lucky Foot means.
Yeah.
What is Yum Heart?
Let's take Magdalene.
Let's try it.
Oh, we start with an item.
Heels one full red heart.
I see.
Very tiny shots.
Decent range.
Beautiful hair.
Four hearts.
Oh, this looks like a winner to me.
Very slow though.
Like, what's the point of this room?
This room boggles my mind.
It makes no sense.
Wait, this... Oh, nevermind.
I thought I just saw a suspicious rock.
Man, I gotta say though, Magdalene, a lot of HP, but...
No damage.
Like, it is so disgusting how bad she is.
Kill this guy.
Can't have him spawn more of those things.
The more I play other characters, the more I want to play Azazel.
Ah, this guy needs to die.
Wow, that was close.
Man, how the fuck?
Come on.
Got him.
Heal up.
Got a bomb.
Ooh, it's time for pills.
Or we buy a ring.
Grab and pick up... Oh, that's good!
Bro, we're absolutely getting that.
Although it would be nice to get a bit of healing as well, so I think I'm gonna buy that.
Oh wait, it costs mana to do this, right?
So it's not just any time I want.
Can I try and pick this up?
Nah, let's not.
You know what, we're gonna try.
Oh!
It totally works!
Motherfucker, why did you throw it down?
Useless!
I was facing down?
Why don't you throw it at your feet, you dummy?
Oh, this is a... Oh, this room, though, is gonna fuck me in the ass!
Hey, you like jars?
What the fuck?
Do I have to... Oh, okay.
Oh, I see.
I understand.
No!
I hate this character!
No more!
We're back to Azazel, dude!
It's Lazarus!
I can't believe it!
What is wrong with me?
But you know what, it's always when you least expect it that everything is gonna go well.
So we're actually gonna win.
Whoa!
That's a chain reaction, yeah!
It's a weird looking level now, again.
Actually, Lazarus is solid.
Lazarus is pretty good.
Oh, this needs to die, yeah.
What's that?
New item!
Freezer baby!
Iced the baby?
What?
Following Familia that fires ice tears.
Experimental pill.
Yeah, see, now it gave me tears up, shot speed down.
So, the experimental pill is definitely randomized.
I like the soundtrack in this place.
Oh, it got frozen!
That's amazing!
Wait, it counts as dead!
I don't even need to do anything to them.
So, what if I go back afterwards?
Oh, man!
So, he's dead.
Alright, I blow up the ice and they're gonna have a bad time.
Yeah, look, it counts as dead.
That's interesting.
Okay, he's gone.
Wait, how did I just...
Oh, no way!
You can push them!
Whoa!
Okay, that's much better.
Very nice.
Wow.
That changes everything.
Oh my god, it's my baby!
We need it.
We need money.
Can we somehow scrounge up 15 coins?
I doubt it.
But I'm gonna try.
Gonna get some HP here.
Thank you.
Ah, should I be going in there?
Yeah.
I think this was a bad idea.
There's no chests or anything.
Yeah, okay.
That was absolutely not worth it.
Oh well.
Two hearts is all I need.
I don't need more than that to beat the boss.
And Lazarus also comes back, right?
Let's not forget.
The haunt!
This is the foreskin man.
But not yet.
First you gotta take care of his children.
Oh shit!
No way!
Ah!
Oh, that's big!
Watch this!
Yeah!
Come to me!
Beautiful!
We get to heal up and grab a sty.
Insane range on this.
But only to the right eye.
Well, that's fine, I guess.
Wait, hold on.
Bro, will you stop shooting so I can tell which ones I'm...
Okay, so I see.
I shoot two types of projectiles right now.
One is a bit bigger than the other.
Um, okay.
Moving on.
So far, so good.
There's a timer on this!
Let's go fast!
Speed run!
Here we go!
Find the boss room!
Oh no, this is a horrible room.
Yeah, you like ice?
Oh, it's actually so good!
The ice is incredible!
Freeze him, freeze him!
Freeze up!
There we go.
Suck on that.
Amazing.
That's not a boss.
We go.
Speed, speed, speed, speed, speed.
Lovely!
Oh, TNT!
Money!
This way!
We're in a corner!
Quick!
No boss yet.
Where's the boss at?
See ya!
Uh, long corridor?
I gotta, I gotta, I gotta go in there though.
I gotta do it.
Whee!
Woo!
Totally worth!
That is crazy.
Oh no, I thought I could push him.
There we go.
Boss time, go!
Dooka flies, it's totally cool.
Yeah, freeze him.
Beautiful.
I think maybe we are too slow for whatever the timer is.
It's probably like a really tight timer.
If it is indeed like a timing thing.
Man, look at that, it's so cool!
Oh!
Oh, the bandage is massive!
Okay, well, I don't know if we did it.
I think we would probably know if we did.
Let's go back.
I also do wonder if there's like a hidden system where the less rooms you clear, the easier the boss is.
So for example, if you choose to do the boss early, by finding it early, maybe it's much easier.
Okay.
These guys are gonna shoot tears.
Massive.
What's that?
Glocoma.
Blind, what was that?
A chance to fire concussive tears that confuse enemy struck.
Confusion applied by this item lasts much longer.
Okay, okay, okay.
Not bad.
That's pretty decent.
Alright.
This one's gonna be tough.
Maybe.
You caused a chain reaction with this.
It's really neat.
Alright, let's go to the store, because we're rich.
Money in the bank.
Ahh!
Fuck this little poop.
Tear of cloth.
Spawns two red horse.
Nah.
I like my son more.
I'm gonna blow this guy up.
What if I blow this up?
Wait a minute.
Hopefully I didn't just redo...
So I had 143, I think, in the machine?
143, let's keep that in mind.
143.
Let's see if it's actually less next time.
I think I may have just...
What do you call it?
Withdrawn a bit of money from the bank.
Oh, this rock!
Boom!
I saw that.
Nothing hides from me.
Okay, we got a timer again.
Speed run!
Be as fast as possible.
Find the boss room.
It's down here.
Just make them freeze them.
Freeze them!
Good enough.
Man,
what a shit room though.
Okay.
Boss is down here, trust.
I'm kind of in a bad spot.
Nice.
Sure, why not?
Nah, not there.
It's here.
Envy.
If we can freeze them, it's huge.
He doesn't do anything.
Oh.
Oh, this is that guy.
Okay, I see.
If we can freeze some of these, that would be fantastic.
We stunned them though, somehow.
A pill?
No.
That's unfortunate.
Okay, whatever timer was on here, I think we...
We're too late.
Come on, poke your head out.
Man, you have a lot of HP.
Dude, I love the ice effect.
Makes the ice thing so much better.
I have no damage.
I really need to find some kind of damage here.
Come on.
I hate these worms.
Pop out.
There we go.
Ooh, what the hell is this?
Causal chain reaction, please.
Where did that blue heart come from?
I think something just dropped.
Yeah, a heart, okay.
Man, I was gonna find the boss so fast and I still haven't found it.
Oh, here it is.
Gamer!
No!
I jinxed.
I'm going in.
It's time for the chubby to come out.
Bombs.
This boss is actually kind of difficult.
Wow, it drops a lot of hearts.
Wait, why is that happening?
I need to remind myself.
Ah, that one, the bandage.
That's true.
Bandage is actually kind of good.
Why is nothing getting frozen?
There we go.
Wow.
Stuck in a corner there.
Ah!
Ah, there we go.
Not too shabby.
Dog!
Desert.
Nice!
Good upgrade.
But I'm not done exploring.
You gotta get all the upgrades as you can.
The more, the better.
How is that happening?
Oh my god.
This guy is just so difficult.
Hate him.
Placebo.
Triggers the effect of the pill health.
I don't hold a pill.
Two of hearts.
Wait!
No way.
I gotta heal up first, though.
I don't know if I need to.
I'm gonna try and heal up first, in case it's my active hearts and not my potential maximum heart, you know?
Dude, this is actually gonna... This is gonna be insane.
Okay, we can try this.
So we should be getting...
What?
Eight, nine hearts?
Two hearts.
Oh, that's underwhelming.
What a shit card.
Well, that's very disappointing.
Okay.
The sound of this...
Actually...
A ladder.
And a pill.
I'll take a pill.
Useless.
Absolutely useless.
What if I blow this up?
Oh, don't take my money.
I don't have any more bombs, unfortunately.
I wanna blow up everything.
I just love seeing things.
Go kaput.
Oish!
Go!
No problem.
Oi, oi, oi.
Why is he camouflaged?
Fine.
Man, I need damage.
This is not gonna go well at all if I don't get some damage.
Like, I'm tickling the enemies here.
I'm doing nothing.
Wow, you shoot fast.
Yeah, that's for you.
What a shot.
A silver bar?
Iron bar, damage up, and concussive tears.
That sounds good.
A chance to fire concussive increases with luck, but we're very unlucky.
Lazarus just doesn't have much luck, you know?
Okay.
I think I need some more speed on my shots.
That would be good.
And this room is closed.
But I have an idea.
That I cannot work out...
Alright, this is deactivated.
Yeah.
Let's just leave.
Our job here is done.
We even have some hearts in the boss room we can utilize.
Take that, and this.
Not bad!
Not bad at all.
Okay, so the one after this is going to be timed.
Curse of the blind.
What does that mean?
Whoa!
What the hell, man?
Oh, God.
So many items!
What is happening here?
What is the Emperor?
Oh, the one that takes me to the boss room, right.
We're going to blow up all of this.
Oh, I don't have any bombs left!
Hmm.
Oh,
wait.
Dude, we can save the Emperor for the timed thingy.
Assuming I'm right about that.
Okay, so right now we have to remember that is up here.
I'm going to use this on this floor.
Okay, he's down.
These are the most dangerous enemies.
Man, I hate them so much.
He's down.
Okay, Jesus Christ.
Hey, guys, you like this?
That's for you.
Amazing.
Love it.
I'm going in here because I'm a badass.
Show me...
Well, that wasn't good.
I take it all back.
Bad decision.
Like, this is the hardest enemy in the game.
The guy with the red pants.
I hate him so much.
His shots are impossible to dodge.
He's hiding all the time.
It's insane.
Wow, I can't get to that.
You like that?
Hey,
come over here.
Come over here.
Wow, he's really confused.
Okay, I guess I'm just going to kill you.
Maybe this is a range to destroy something on the wall.
Doesn't look like it, though.
Man, I love the fucking frost.
It's incredible.
If it wasn't for that, I don't think I would be doing too well right now.
Uh-huh.
Oh.
There's a trap of sorts.
I'm going to wait until he pops.
Look at that!
Strength.
Plus one health to speed that...
That is not bad.
But I think the sun is better.
I'm going to stick with this for now and then we're going to save the sun for the boss.
Question mark.
Best butt.
Sworn protector.
Oh, is it just like a random item?
When it's a question mark.
Upon taking damage spawns, a fly familiar with the current.
For the current room.
That orbits Isaac.
Okay.
You got it.
Cheers, guys.
They're the worst!
Three!
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa, hold on now.
We're going to wait.
We're not going to pick that up yet.
We have big plans here.
Oh, God.
You like ice?
That's for you.
Wonderful.
Not the pants, people.
Bite that abushion!
Fuck!
Wake up.
Oh, God, damn.
Oh, no, there's a horde.
I can't take it.
No.
Too bad.
The boss is here.
Not yet.
I could gamble a little bit.
I have money.
But we haven't found the shop room yet.
So that could be an opportunity for us waiting.
You know what's really bad when you have low damage?
A lot of enemies.
Like, close by, you know?
Because you can't clear them out fast enough.
In fact, everything is just worse with low damage.
Which is unsurprising.
It's not really a very insightful statement.
Money bags.
Hey, I needed those.
Bombs.
Good stuff.
I'm going to blow them up because I hate them.
Absolutely worth it.
Oh, my God.
Somehow I cleared that room without taking any damage.
No!
There's no nightmare!
I don't know what to do here.
And go.
Nice.
That is so huge.
Oh, no.
This is not a shop room.
Oh, wait a minute.
Did I destroy this guy earlier?
Is that why he's here now?
Is he... Look at... He has the noose around his neck.
We came back.
I thought it was over.
Thank the lord above.
Oh, man.
I need healing.
Go to the arcade.
We're going to gamble our way to health.
The hell is that?
We will all die one day.
It's like a fortune machine?
Well, that was worthless.
When life gives you lemons, reroll!
Hold on.
I need to do this.
I need healing.
What?
It just blew up?
The devil in disguise.
Do not look so hurt.
Others have problems too.
Your princess is in another castle.
I know that reference!
Uh...
Mario.
Okay, so we do get something out of this.
You were born wrong.
I mean...
I've had that before.
Sun rays on your little finger?
Trust no one.
True!
Your soul is hidden deep within the darkness.
Blew!
Oh!
Go to the next room.
Okay.
Shit!
I thought it was a slight hint.
Bring him the photo.
Who?
What photo?
Nice!
Follow the cat.
Do not lose your head.
Good advice.
Think for yourself.
Even better.
Again?
Come on, man.
That's a scam.
Use bombs wisely?
I will.
There you go.
I'm gonna kill this guy as well.
Everyone dies.
Okay.
We're done.
Now we go pick up all the necessary ingredients for the cake we're about to bake.
And it'll be tasty.
It's a banana cake.
I have to remember now.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
We do boss first.
Right.
Boss first.
We're actually gonna take the sun for this.
Because this will heal us if shit goes wrong.
Yep.
Wait a minute.
I have an idea.
No, I was about to say if I put a bomb here, it's gonna blow it out, but it's not.
It's just gonna stay in there.
Here we go.
It's Peep!
He's not gonna have a chance against us, though.
He does poison?
Interesting.
Wait,
why does it keep jumping on the same spot?
Not a problem at all.
Marion.
Oh, oh!
I didn't mean to pick it up, but okay.
There we go.
Let's go back.
We're not gonna grab the heart.
And check this out.
Check this out.
Are you ready for the ultimate play?
Uh, blow the scale.
The ultimate play is coming up.
We'll see what I mean.
Uh, here.
The ultimate play.
Yoink!
Next room has a timer on it.
Let's try this once and for all.
You know what I'm about to do, right?
We're going in.
I like that he just jumps down and dies in that little movie.
Boom!
Monstro 2!
I want you to attack me!
That's for you.
Aww, he dodged it.
Insane.
Oh!
Right, he does that stuff.
Okay.
Oh my god, oh my god, I'm so bad.
He jumps again.
And now he jump again and you're gonna land there.
Now he comes here.
How do I keep missing the laser?
Dude, I'm playing so bad.
Okay, so when he squeezes, that's when the laser comes.
The squeezes laser.
I see now.
I missed it again.
This is a tough boss ass.
I meant tough ass boss, but tough boss ass is also kind of cool.
I'll take it.
I saw it coming!
I saw it coming.
And?
Nothing special?
Matchbook, a black card, three bombs, boo.
Evil up.
Okay, but why is my evil not up?
I'm assuming the demon stat on the left is my evil.
Sure.
Well, okay, now we can start clearing.
Whoa, okay, calm down, calm down.
Calm down.
Oh, yeah, the chain reaction is crazy.
Oh, the red stuff, it damages me.
Oh, well, there goes that heart.
Wait, what's this?
I don't even know how I'm taking damage.
What was that?
How did I just do that?
They're like camouflaged.
Camouflaged crybabies.
Stuff of nightmares.
That is Synthoid?
No, it's the virus.
Poison's enemies on contact?
That sounds pretty bad.
I mean, I don't want to contact them at all.
The last thing I want to do, what's that?
Blood in a jar?
I think I'll save up for it.
Oh, we almost have enough.
Let's get one more coin.
Are you going to charge?
Okay.
Okay, don't step in the red stuff.
Huge.
I'm not going to go in there.
There's stock over there.
Whoa!
Bro, that's crazy!
Insane room.
Oh, wow.
This is where we started, actually.
Oh, okay.
Wait a minute.
Hold on.
That's how that works.
Very nice.
Look at me.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, wait, I was going to save my money.
Why am I death playing like an idiot?
I'm on autopilot.
What's that?
Golden horseshoe.
15% chance for the treasure rooms.
Ooh.
That sounds pretty good.
I like that.
I don't like the worms.
Oh, my God.
I will actually die.
Do I have any HP?
I don't.
Yeah, it's bad.
It's bad.
Mom.
Oh, no way.
We're leaving.
We're getting out of here.
Wait a minute.
No, no, we come back.
We have a we have a resurrect.
We're chilling.
No problem.
Come on, then, Mom.
Show me what you got.
Oh, God.
Somehow we made it.
We froze our hands or feet.
I don't know.
Stomp your hands.
Clap your feet.
A brand new dance.
Somehow we're still alive.
I don't know how or why.
Oh, no, this is going to be a shitty room to deal with.
Oh, no.
Oh, my God.
It's over.
Maybe.
Freeze them.
Freeze them all.
Holy shit.
Wow.
We're actually in danger.
The smart thing to do would be to continue on to the next level, I think.
Whoa.
A room with a dice on it.
We got to try it.
Six.
I've had this before, but I forgot what it did.
Wait, let's not step.
Wait a minute.
Do it.
We got two luck.
Oh, we got new items.
Quintz.
Conjoined.
The first five enemies killed in each room will spawn a random friendly baby familiar.
Familiar spawn by this effect are stationary.
Okay, okay.
Placenta.
I wonder if me picking up these things via this method, counts as me identifying the items for later.
More health.
Heals one red heart.
It didn't heal me at all.
Oh, I guess it's only...
Oh, okay, that's bad then.
Range lock soul heart.
Familiar.
Tears sized down.
The wig.
Depression, oh no.
Cloud familiar that follows Isaac and spawns a trail of damaging blue creep.
Enemies that touch the cloud have a chance to be struck by a damaging light beam.
That's cool.
Caffeine pill.
Spawns a random pill.
Oh, when you pick it up, I guess.
Latch key, anti-gravity.
Tears will hover in place while pressing attack button?
Huh?
Releasing attack button will shoot all hovering...
That sounds crazy.
Whoa!
That's cool.
I like that a lot.
Oh God, look at the...
Dude, the caffeine, is that what's causing the ice?
That's incredible.
We are fucking tweaking right now.
This doesn't look too good though.
I think we may have to move on to the next level.
But no.
Wait, why is this chest closed?
Did I already open that?
Oh, it's so weird the way...
Oh, okay, actually, maybe I don't like this very much then.
Hmm.
I'm gonna get some bombs.
Wait, why did it make that sound when I picked up the bombs?
We're probably dead here.
Wait, what?
They died?
How?
Come on.
Oh my God!
It's actually kind of crazy.
Fuck about burst.
Holy shit.
Let me blow up some walls.
Ah, unlucky.
Where do I go?
I'm very fast now.
I'm very fast.
I'm tiny and fast.
You can't catch me.
There's a room down here that I cannot enter.
I can go this way.
Let's find some HP.
There we go.
Oh, those are not bombs.
Wait, what?
I just healed!
Hold on a minute, what's happening?
Something just happened.
Heels... firing has a chance to spawn blue spiders.
50% chance to heal half a red heart every minute?
So what, I can just stand there and wait?
Oh wait, that was not worth it.
Ah, shit.
Okay, whatever.
What if I go back in here?
Can I roll again?
Let me roll again.
Again and again.
So it's just going to heal me here in like 20 seconds?
Or not, I guess.
There's still a room we didn't explore.
Whoa!
Yo!
Huge!
What's happening with my...
Wait a minute!
Why is all my shit bouncing all around?
I need to understand what is going on here.
Is it... maybe it's the Boiled Baby.
Boiled Baby!
What a name!
Oh, what the fuck?
Alright, well I... hold on.
Okay, I'm not sure what's...
I healed!
Wait, what?
Fragmented card!
New floors will generate an additional secret room!
Whoo!
I need that!
Wait, wait, wait.
Actually, no.
I would rather have this, because I don't have any methods to discover secret rooms.
I'm thinking about synergies here.
I'm smart.
Alright, we're going to go in here now and move on.
This is Mom!
It's Mom time!
We got to focus now.
Necropolis?
That's new.
Oh my god, oh my god!
AHHH!
I don't know what's happening!
Wait, this guy has a crown on him!
Huh?
I... I don't know what's going on in this game!
I don't know what's happening!
Now we're not going to miss... miss-click.
It's time for the real...
the only true character in this game.
Azazel!
No more losing!
Instant win now.
Oh, I have to remember how to play this guy.
Look how good that is!
This character is OP!
Oh my god!
I'm so close!
Come here, you.
Oh look, I can just pick all this up, because I can just fly through shit.
I'm the destroyer of poop as well.
That's going to preserve my black hearts.
Let's rock this place!
Speaking of rocks...
No, okay, that is suspicious.
I feel like there should be a secret room there.
Just keep moving!
Drive by!
Wonderful!
We take this, of course.
I think I've had that thing before.
No, I haven't.
Unicorn stomp.
You feel stumped.
Gain invincibility and bonus speed for five seconds.
Disable tears while active.
Actually, it could be good if you want to get through spikes or something.
That's the one time I can see that being good.
This is a special key.
I don't have money.
But I could have money.
Nice.
Somehow I didn't get hit.
I was a bit lucky.
Huge.
That's five coins.
We're going to be rich now.
Ah, not that rich.
Easy room.
Oh, look at this!
Special rock detected.
Special rock.
Oh, we don't have any bombs again.
You've got to be kidding me.
How is this real?
Guess we're going to kill the boss.
Uh-oh, this guy is tough.
Nice try.
Oh, he's actually not that bad.
He's easy as hell.
Whoa, wow.
Wow.
Ball of bandages.
That's a lot of stuff.
Shots deal damage, deals contact damage, fires charm shots.
I mean, when are you ever going to find four of these in a run that sounds impossibly impossible?
Okay.
Sure.
I didn't mean to jump in!
Okay, well, there it is.
Too bad.
No, I have no key.
This is a disaster.
Wow.
Beautiful.
A pill.
We love those.
Oh, more healing!
Or, I mean, hearts, where Journey begins.
That's also good.
Very nice.
There's like a grace period after they burrow where you can still hit them, it seems.
Thank you.
Uh, let's check what's in there.
Oh, I can't.
Man, I need keys.
I really messed up going through the latch so fast.
Wow, chain reaction there.
Whoa!
Hey, come over here.
Actually, I'm going to kill you up here.
You're not going to cooperate?
Come on.
There we go.
Come here.
Ah, they don't care about me at all, it seems.
There we go.
Oh, I missed.
No secrets up there.
Worth a shot, though.
Wait, what?
Ha, what the fuck?
I mean, okay.
Get some more wisdom from this thing.
Ah, should I?
What do you want to do today?
Play Isaac!
Always your head in the clouds.
True.
Blister!
Tears have increased knockback.
Hey!
Cool.
Your soul is hitting deep.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Take your medicine.
I'm trying.
Don't leave the house today.
I don't plan to.
A bank man brings you no luck today.
Huh?
Or a hank man.
Live to die.
You're playing it wrong.
Give me the controller.
Joke's on you.
I'm not even using a controller.
Follow the dog.
Why so blue?
This thing is so wrong.
Hey!
We got something.
The emperor.
Boss room.
Oh well.
No bombs to blow it up either.
That's just unfortunate.
Jesus!
Now we can take our medicine.
Nice!
So shots speed up.
I guess it's just gonna recharge speed in my case.
Wait, what does my active do?
Invincibility, that's right.
I really should be using that.
No, I need keys!
We got a key.
What should I be using it on this?
Or should I be using it on the item room?
Wait a second.
I'm gonna save it for the item room.
Here.
Money.
Okay, they can't shoot through the wall, that's good.
Makes it easy for me.
Now we go back.
I wanna see what's in that item room.
Or treasure room.
Wait a minute, so why is this... you see the sun rays up top?
There's light rays coming in here.
I feel like that is symbolic of something.
Fuck me!
That hurt me.
Guess that was too close.
Item room.
Yeah, here we go!
What's that?
That is a... some kind of award.
Dead Eye.
Accuracy brings power.
Grants a stacking damage bonus for each successive shot that hits an enemy up to 2x damage.
Each missed shot has a chance to reset the bonus.
I mean, with...
with this character, it should be pretty easy to always hit something.
Shouldn't be a big problem.
Now I need to be super accurate.
Sweet.
That's the key for the chest.
Wait, you know what I could do?
I know... check this out.
Oh!
Fuck!
I thought this room was cleared.
I wasn't even looking.
I'm gonna show you a fantastic plan here.
Uh... go up here, right?
Nah, not there.
Wait, how do I do this best?
No.
Go over here now.
Go down here.
Then we go inside of this room.
Mom's foot stomps down.
I don't want that, honestly.
So, fuck it.
Here we go!
One, two, and three... no.
Motherfucker!
You were delayed!
Fuck you!
Unbelievable.
Okay, there we go.
Eye drops...
increases the fire rate from eye six, left eye.
I don't know how fire rate affects this beam.
Doesn't make any sense to me.
Whoa, is that a dead cat?
Oh my god, what do I pick?
Ooh, shit.
I'm trying this.
I think I realized it caused the three.
Fuck me.
That doesn't count.
That one does not count at all.
I had no idea it worked like that, now I do.
The wafer.
Damage risk... wait, what?
It uses all damage to...
Whoa!
That's kind of crazy.
Right?
Isn't that a massive upgrade?
I pretty much can't die.
The chariots.
For six seconds, become invincible.
Speed, deal 40... ooh!
Just run through enemies.
Wait, what did I have?
Oh, teleport... oh, you know what?
Hey, hey, hey!
Oh, unfair!
I had nowhere to go, man.
Actually unfair.
Okay.
Now give me that.
All right, all right, all right.
That's for me.
What is that?
Squeezy, more tears than soul hearts.
Lovely.
What a fantastic start so far, huh?
Can't be mad about that at all.
This is like the best.
Let's try and find some coins here.
I feel like some rooms just have a lot of coins in the poop.
Others have none.
Unbelievable.
Wait, what do I have right now?
Oh, yeah.
Good.
I actually didn't mean to go in here.
I'm going too fast.
Nice.
Get dodged, nerd.
Oh!
Okay, you got me there.
Hold on.
Placenta.
Oh!
That's the one I just had.
That's good.
It just heals me.
But we're not done.
Not by a long mile, as they say.
Should we?
No, we're not going to try that.
Then again, what about the invincibility?
Uh-oh.
Oh, wait, I can just...
Haha!
I kind of want to blow things up, though.
Where is the safe spot?
Do we even have a safe spot here?
We do have a safe spot.
If I destroy this up here, it's going to run around and we quickly walk north.
Ready?
Oi!
Sick!
Gaming.
Okay, some kind of mask that's crying.
Wait, this guy's really tiny.
Why is he tiny?
I think I want to go...
Out!
We're done here.
Yep, no more.
Let's-a-go!
That was a fantastic floor!
Alright, basement two.
This door is locked.
We have a hundred percent...
I don't understand this demon mechanic.
Like, at all.
Like, what determines...
When it goes up and down, it's super random, it seems.
Oh, this is made for Azazel.
Look at him cleaning up.
Very nice.
Taking a look at the rocks.
I see nothing sus.
Moving on.
So good.
The sus rocks.
Oh, here we go!
We got one!
Let me put it here so we also have a chance of destroying a door.
Oh!
Cool.
Item?
No, we don't have a key!
Insane.
Bye-bye.
Thank you.
Look at me just grabbing everything because I can fly.
Come on, key me.
A key.
Jumping jacks.
I mean...
Are we going to find a key at all here, or what?
This seems kind of like a joke.
Like, I want to get that item.
Hello?
Do I just start blowing up random shit hoping that I get a key?
I'm looking for more sus rocks.
Like, with all of these rocks, there's got to be something.
That door's closed.
We could go in here.
I'm going to try and blow this up.
I'm going to step on this.
I don't know.
This room is confounding to me.
It doesn't make any...
Like, you would think there would be some sort of reward for stepping on that thing, right?
Nope.
Nuh-uh.
Man, fuck!
I want to get in there!
Oh, I tried that already.
Dang it.
Okay, I guess it's over.
Let's keep moving on.
No item for me.
It's Larry Jr. Is there a Larry Sr.?
And where is he?
Wow, this boss was pretty easy.
Grant's a stat increase based on whichever one is the lowest.
And pickup drops one pickup that Isaac has the least of.
That's a key!
The gods have answered my prayers.
I could also go in there.
I'll come back.
I'm gonna get this item first.
We need to see what we can get here.
Oh, what is that?
Headless baby!
What is with these babies?
Boiled baby?
Headless baby?
Following familiar that generates a trail of damaging creep.
Okay, that sounds pretty good.
Do I want to sacrifice a heart?
To get an item, though, is the question.
Oh, wait, it's gone!
Oh, you can only do it.
Oh, I see.
Okay, fuck.
Oh, well, lesson learned.
It's probably the same with the Heaven Rooms, then.
This one has a timer.
But I don't have a key.
Infested.
That's fine.
Oh, keys!
Massive.
No, not these.
Okay, actually, with a Zazel, it's totally fine.
Another key.
Time to go to the library.
How to chop?
Ooh!
Ah, on a Zazel, of course, I get it on a Zazel.
And this one is the Book of Sin, sponsor random pickup.
That sounds good.
I do like random pickups.
Lovely!
This guy wants to eat my keys.
He can go eat his... or eat my butt.
There's no way I'm giving him my keys.
The belt!
I'm fast as hell.
Next up, we're gonna find the monocle.
Also gives you speed.
Peek a pretty head up!
Oh, fantastic.
Special key!
Massive.
By the way, I just had an idea.
For the chariots.
Is it worth it?
No, it's not worth it.
My idea is not worth it.
That was actually so close.
Yay!
You want coins?
You're not gonna get it.
Look at me just going around.
Mega Man!
Wait, isn't that an actual video game character?
You're gonna... Come on.
Oh, you're spawning things?
Okay.
I can't believe that.
Here we go.
Dodge it nice.
It's not too bad at all.
We're chilling here.
Easy.
I feel like I get this so often.
Aw, it was all shitty coins.
And a flat penny.
Wealth of answers?
25% chance to spawn a key each time you pick up a coin.
Chances increased with nickels and dimes.
Wait, I don't know what's worth more, a nickel or a dime.
I'm not in the American States knowledge of currency.
I think a nickel is the smallest, right?
A dime is the currency worth more?
Wait, wait!
Oh, they're taking damage from the creep I make!
Yo, you can totally kite enemies crazy that way.
Let's see.
A mushroom.
God's flesh.
Shrink shot.
A chance to fire tears that temporarily shrink enemies.
How is that good?
Strunken enemies attempt to flee and can be crushed by walking...
Oh, okay, that's how it's good.
Crushed by walking over them, huh?
Very cool.
This makes me happy.
I do have money, let's go to the shop.
In fact, I have a lot of money.
Question mark!
More options?
There's options.
Wait, really?
One additional item will appear in treasure rooms.
Only one item can be chosen.
Wouldn't it be funny if this actually revealed an extra option in the menu?
Like, imagine.
That would be hilarious.
Is there an extra option?
I actually don't know.
I don't remember what was here before.
But wouldn't that be funny?
That would be so funny.
Um, I'm done here.
I didn't mean to give you that coin, you ass.
Okay, fine.
Keep eating them, then.
Give me an item, though.
Say goodbye.
Thanks.
Oh, wait, I had the map open.
Uh, time we moved on, I think.
No, no, I had an idea.
Check it out, check it out.
This is sick.
No damage taken?
Oh, wait, that sucks.
Boom, baby!
That was the plan, that was the genius.
That was it.
I think it was smart.
But I forgot that it was actually a shitty room.
Okay.
Oh, what is... Oh, that is, uh...
Dice!
Wait, I don't want to do that.
I don't want to fuck things up.
No thanks.
Not for me.
Bible tracked?
3% increased chance of finding internal hearts.
Wait, what was the other one?
Uh...
Sponic?
No, you know what?
I have so many keys.
I'm taking this.
I like that.
Wait.
Oh, wait, you're still alive.
Oh.
Precharge it?
Also, what was the active item I had?
Oh yeah, pickup.
Thanks.
Oh yeah, they do become smaller.
So wait, I can walk, but this is a bomb, so maybe it's not a good idea to walk on them?
Let me try.
Haha!
Sick.
Definitely opening this door.
Uh...
Weird room.
I have a feeling, but I have two bombs.
I gotta save them.
Save the bombs.
Nice.
Wait, I have a...
Oh.
Dude, I was panicking for a little...
for a brief second there.
I looked at my HP...
and I thought I had one HP left.
Because it looks like the black hearts are like empty ones.
You know what I mean?
Jesus Christ.
False alarm.
Oh god.
That was close.
Okay.
Up here.
Ah, wait, wait, wait.
Sick.
Yeah, these guys are no problem on Azazel.
A supercharged fly or something?
What's that?
Or a massive heart?
What could be best?
I already have a familiar.
Maybe that's gonna...
make it even better.
Let's try.
Flamboyant protector.
Okay, it is just a familiar.
Fly familiar that moves rapidly to block most enemy shots that come close to Isaac.
Ooh.
And there's a brief cooldown period after blocking enough shots.
Well, depending on how that actually happens, this could either be...
amazing or absolutely terrible.
Oh wait, there's still...
Oh, they're so small you can't even see the little...
I see what's happening now.
Oh god.
Okay.
Wait, is he still here?
Is he just tiny?
I don't understand.
Okay, he's gone.
Man, I don't think I like the one that shrinks the enemies.
They're too small, like I can barely see them on the screen.
I actually hate that item.
Is that the one I have in the bottom left?
No, it's not the BLI.
Like, see, he's not dead.
He's just sort of tiny now.
Wait, maybe they are dead.
Oh, okay.
Useless.
I'm trying to pay attention to this fly.
I don't seem to be doing anything.
Wishbone, five percent chance when taking damage to destroy the trinket and spawn an item from the current room's pool.
No, thanks.
That sounds horrible.
I'll take a coin.
He wants bombs?
I say no.
Ah, is this worth this?
Probably.
Oh my god, a cord?
Ah, should I buy the pill?
Yeah, we're going for... I love the pill.
Yeah!
Pills are always good.
Well, not always, but pretty much always.
There's not a room I missed.
No!
Motherfucker ate my...
Okay, that's actually okay.
Thanks.
It totally just takes care of the projectiles.
Whoa!
Very nice.
I like this familiar.
Dude, I'm speeding through the levels.
Look at me.
Go!
It's the chop!
He's going to get chopped up by my laser beam.
He's not going to stand a chance against me.
I am powerful.
Oh my god, I'm killing him!
Thanks.
Synth oil.
Damage?
Oh, that's just straight up good.
I mean, you can't really say anything else to that.
Okay.
Now it's necropolis.
Oh!
The laser.
Jesus Christ.
Insane.
It spawns a pill.
But it's a useless pill.
I thought it could only spawn...
Wait, hold on, he's going to...
There we go.
I thought it could only spawn like one of the three items you have on the left.
Like coins, bombs, or keys.
No!
Okay, wow, that was a significant decrease!
Rough!
Crazy.
That was a massive debuff there.
Oh god.
Here we go.
Oh
god.
What the frick is happening?
Kill this guy.
Whoa, whoa, look at these guys!
That's a new enemy.
Ooh, I'm losing a lot of HP for no reason right now.
I think I'm getting a little too... excited, you know?
I need to slow down a bit.
There's no reason to be this crazy.
Yeah, go into my red stuff!
Come here!
Oh yeah!
Lovely.
Oh, okay, he's dead.
Ahh, down here.
Oh, coin for me.
God damn it.
He's tiny, right?
So I can... That's the thing, I don't want to risk it.
It's too risky.
Oh, enemies.
What is that?
What is this?
Ooh, I think I want the blue one.
Taurus, speed down plus rage is... building?
Huh?
While in a room with enemies, Isaac gains a stacking speed bonus over time.
Once per room, when maximum speed is reached, Isaac gains invincibility for 5 seconds.
When the invincibility is active, Isaac deals contact damage.
Oh my god, that is way too much.
I can't keep track of that shit in the middle of combat.
I'm a simple man, I can't do that.
Absolutely not.
Shit item.
I'm losing all of my HP.
I got a card.
The sun!
Massive.
What's this?
Moms lock it.
Heal for half red heart whenever Isaac unlocks something.
Where's half red heart drops into whole red hearts?
I like it more than this one, I think.
These guys have some nice butts.
Oh, we got maximum speed!
Well, that was it, right?
Oh no.
Versus greed.
I mean, I have so much money.
Wait, there's a room to the right down here?
Huh?
Wait, what?
Oh my god!
I was looking at the wrong part of the map.
I was looking at the top left.
I thought I was in somewhere completely different.
Never mind.
I was completely losing my mind there.
Okay.
Alright then.
Back to it.
I kinda wanna get some more health upgrades.
Just more health.
I don't like the black health very much.
Oh shit.
Oh my god.
Alright, not too bad.
Dude, this fly is actually kinda doing work.
Thanks.
Bomb for me.
I've seen this room before.
I mean, wait, I can't take damage.
What am I doing?
Give me something not justice.
Sponsor one heart, key bomb a coin.
It spawns everything?
I thought it said one ore.
I'll take it.
He went to space!
And we got a box.
Sponsor red heart, key bomb, coin, pill, card, a rune, and a trinket on pickup.
Wow.
Okay then.
Doubles Isaac's red hearts.
Yeah, that's a fake.
Doesn't work at all.
Speed up is good.
The sun is good.
This is good.
If Einlich has only one empty heart, containers.
Heals one heart.
Oh, has only empty.
No.
We move on.
The sun is gonna come in handy.
Big.
Now, should I go in there?
No.
Bad idea.
It's time for boss.
And hopefully we get some kind of item that gives us more HP.
Here we go.
Mask of Infamy.
Oh, he's gonna separate.
Yeah, yeah.
Whoa.
Oh my God.
Look at this here.
I'm too scared.
I know how long it lasts.
Okay, that's...
Wow.
There we go.
One lock.
Oh, there we go.
More health.
Oh.
Angels.
Wow.
A holy book.
Wait, it's the Bible.
Straight up.
Gain flight for the current room.
Boo.
I want this instead.
Yeah.
Wait, why does it still say two out of three?
Do I have another book?
Oh, maybe it's just the ones I've touched.
I've touched this book.
So...
Therefore, it's two out of three.
So if I find it on the book, we're gonna become a bookworm.
Let's go!
Yeah, we get an extra heart.
Oh, that's so good.
Wait, I almost used the key on that rock.
I didn't mean to, but I almost did.
Huh?
Scam.
Whoa.
Pay to win.
Treasure rooms will always contain a restock machine.
Brother.
That sounds crazy.
I need more money then.
Pay to win.
That's funny.
I'm gonna run over you.
See, it didn't count there.
You can't rely on this shit.
Myosodus, up to four, uncollected pickups from the previous floor...
will spawn in the starting room of a new floor.
Huh?
No, I like this.
I wanna pay to win.
Oh my god.
Because I clearly need it!
Oh, here we go!
Mega Man style!
Or whatever, isn't that what Mega Man does?
Sick.
Boom!
Good stuff.
More money.
Oh right, I can't destroy that.
No way!
How lucky is that?
Buttons!
Uh oh.
Oh, they all died, okay.
More bombs, that means I can test for more secrets here.
No way!
Oh, maybe this was a room I could have entered anyway.
Look at the tiny flies!
Death!
Wait, what was the other one?
Oh, the sun.
I'll use death.
The Necromonicon has appeared.
Wow, they all just died!
Cool.
Now I grab this.
Oh wait.
Why is my thing not charging?
Oh, I couldn't do it while I was in Mario mode or something.
Something's wrong with this room.
Maybe.
Okay.
Guess not.
I hate this item that makes the enemy smaller.
I really do.
It is horrible.
Wait, what is making that sound?
Oh, it's just my creep, I think.
Wait, they're still enemies.
Oh, he was almost invisible.
I see.
Teleport secret room.
Blow this.
No way.
Hold on, before I go that way.
Wrap this card again.
Oh wait.
Well, that was dumb.
Oops.
Whoopsie.
Uh, now we go here.
Oh, yeah, I can't charge it while I'm in this mode.
That's what's happening.
Mmm, kay.
Ah, I should've saved the teleport, I guess, for this stuff.
Mistakes.
Double active?
Wait, what?
I don't know what just happened.
I guess it did what my active did.
Right?
And this one is...
Teleports to the...
Oh, there we go!
Aw, I didn't see those spiky rocks.
That was a mistake.
But I guess I'll save this, then.
Uh-oh, what's this?
Oh, here we go.
Yeah, I don't like that item, either.
Okay.
Man, where's the item room here?
I wanna pay to win.
Wait, my creep looks exactly like theirs.
Dice room?
Absolutely not.
Uh...
Oh, here we go, here we go!
Whoa!
Explosivo!
25% chance to fire a sticky tear.
It will grow and explode for 60 damage when attached to an enemy.
Mom's contacts.
More range.
I mean, they're both good.
Do I have to choose, or can I...
Wait, what did this item say?
Treasure rooms will always contain a restock machine.
I don't see a restock machine.
No, I can't abo- What is the point, then?
God, fuck, I wanted the other one.
I wanted range.
That's way more important.
Why was there no restock machine?
Mom's two red hearts.
Uh, go in here.
What's this?
Candy?
Candy in a jar?
A little baggie.
Extra pill room.
Oh, no way!
Oh, wait, I don't want range down.
Oh, I don't want that.
Where's my card?
Oh, wait, we have this.
And now we have an Icy, so we can hold two pills.
Get that one!
Nice, I'm gonna buy this, too.
And what was this?
Minus one range?
We don't like that.
Where's my card?
Oh, it's back here, I think.
Actually, hold on.
I do want to go in here.
I don't have to click on the dice, right?
It's two.
I don't know if I should try it.
Nah.
It's probably- Okay, the number of eyes on the die probably determines how many items get re-rolled.
So six means six items, right?
That's how that works.
What's this?
Infested?
Sponsor friendly spider for each enemy in the room, or one to three if there are no enemies.
Ah, okay.
That's cool.
I like that.
But how do we...
Didn't I have a card somewhere that had like a teleport to the boss room?
Where the hell did that card go?
This is so confusing right now.
It just disappeared.
I can't see it on the map at all.
It's gone.
Okay, I guess we're doing boss.
And then we can spawn some spiders.
It's Mom!
Okay, okay.
Oh, here we go.
What's damaging me?
I think we got it.
Yeah, very good, very good.
This guy's still here.
What's that?
Mom's pearls!
More range!
Oh, that's so good!
Let's see the range now.
Okay, definitely better.
Definitely better.
We have a demon room.
If I don't enter now, we can't return.
I'm entering now.
Rotten baby generates blue flies and some... question mark?
Two hearts.
So here's the question.
Does it consume my blue, black or red?
It's an experiment.
Let's see.
It takes my red.
Shit, what did I do?
Eye of the occult.
Damage, range, minus shot speed.
Tears can be controlled in mid-flight.
Wait, what?
Oh, my God!
Okay, that's kind of sick, though.
I'm digging that.
It's kind of... I mean, can I stop shooting, maybe, or...?
Hello, stop shooting.
Stop, stop!
Wait, does range even matter?
I'm just going to eat this pill.
Fuck it.
I have infinite range.
What do you mean?
Hello?
All right.
Well, that's going to significantly change the playstyle here.
Curse of the unknown?
Uh-oh.
Wait, now it stops.
And it starts when I... Okay.
Oh, it's when I leave a room, I see.
Oh, this is going to mess me... Wait, I can't move it!
My attack thing is stuck!
Huh?
Wait, I'm confused.
What's... My hearts?
What's with my hearts?
What is happening?!
I don't understand nothing!
This just turned into a fucking... whatever is happening.
Like, what is going on?
I can't move my attack.
It's bugged.
I don't understand.
Thanks.
Oh, what the...?
Is there a button somewhere?
Oh, there's a button.
Okay.
They all have bombs on them?!
What is going on?!
Wait, what was this?
Hearts?
Sure, why not?
This is crazy.
Now I can't move it again.
I gotta be in between them or something.
It's weird as hell.
The virus?
Sure.
Okay, I don't like whatever is happening right now.
This is horrible.
We gotta find the boss and just do it, like, right now.
I can't move my friggin' attack!
There's something going on here.
As soon as combat starts, I can't move this attack thingy.
Yeah, now it's stuck again.
I don't get it.
Now I can move it again.
Oh, we're bossing.
Jesus Christ.
I have no idea how I'm taking damage.
I don't know what's happening.
This is a shit show.
I can't move it!
Fuck!
Tonsil, whatever.
Don't give me this.
I don't know what's going on, bro.
Holy shit!
I'm just moving around praying to God that something good happens.
Lots of bombs.
I have so many bombs.
Wait, I can't even place bombs!
No, I can't.
Wait, what?!
I'm shooting bomb- wait, I'm so confused, bro.
Oh, wait, my laser is shooting the bomb.
Stop shooting!
Oh, no.
Oh, wait a minute!
I think I understand what's happening!
I get it!
It's whenever the power-up thingy happens.
I can't shoot any way normally doing that.
So I'm actually immune to damage right now.
Oh!
Just fucking go!
The Fallen?!
I mean...
Alright!
There we go!
I get it.
I understand what's happening now.
That took only 10 hours.
I was too focused on things not working.
Man, that is a clusterfuck of whatever is possible.
Just all happened at the same time in this playthrough here.
We're gonna find secrets now.
Maybe down here...
Actually, probably here.
No.
Tonsil?
Should I go in there?
That seems like a bad idea.
There we go!
Oh, look at that.
Bit of gambling.
And we even found a...
We haven't even found a treasure room yet.
Okay, sure.
Nah, I like this.
I'll use my money in a shop room.
Man, I'm so frickin' quick.
Look at this.
Oh, momma's here.
Dude, I'm just...
Yeah.
Smashing through with this.
Nice.
Insanity.
Wait, no, no, no!
Stop shooting!
Why is the bomb being exce- I don't understand that.
Fuck me.
Apparently, there's no- Wait, what is this room?
Why was there- Oh, it's this thing, okay.
I'm gonna blow him up.
Locky Toe has appeared!
Huh?
Head of the keeper, Penny Tears.
Tears that hit enemies have a 5% chance to spot a coin!
Okay, cool.
Well, we're gonna get a lot of coins.
You know what?
Fuck it, I'm going in here.
Just kill them all.
Wait, where are the enemies?
Now we gotta go to the boss.
We cleared everything.
So the question is, do I even want this coin down there?
I'm gonna get this, I guess.
I'm sick now.
Here we go!
Wish me luck.
I didn't mean to pick it up.
Wow, look at that!
Huge!
Here it is!
It's time for the heart.
Whoa, this looks really weird now.
Arcade!
Are we gonna gamble?
Huh?
Oh wait, I can see my health again!
Yeah, Curse of the Unknown was weird as hell and it did things to me.
It did weird things to me.
Hey, refilled my mana and I gave me a yellow!
On the mana bar!
Not sure what that means.
Come on.
Oh, oh, okay.
Wait, is he giving me a second layer on mana?
Even more speed?
Come on!
We're already so fast.
Alright.
Jesus Christ.
I wonder why this thing activates immediately now.
Usually it's like after a while.
I'm not gonna go in there.
Still have enemies?
No.
Oh!
Oh, the colors are so weird.
I didn't realize that was bad poop.
I thought it was the good poop.
Oh no.
I got pills.
Speed... Honestly, I kind of like that.
Slow it down a bit.
It was too much.
Spotting on the battery immediately.
Here we go.
Lock up.
Haha, cool.
Wow, he died fast.
This is one of those runs where I don't even know what's happening half the time.
I'm just going along with it, you know?
There's the boss.
Should we just go for it?
Let's go for it, man.
The heart, are you ready?
Kill these smaller ones.
And now we just wish for the best.
Oh my god.
We did it!
We have done it!
Oh, wait, how did I just...
I just stopped doing it, somehow.
Oh, there we go.
You press control.
There we go!
It's time for the butt again.
Oh, lovely butt.
The clothes hanger!
How many of these do they have?
That is so weird.
Okay, okay.
Slowly unlocking more and more.
But that's going to be the end of that.
Guys, we're getting better.
Two runs, or two wins.
The first one was convincing, it was smooth, it was clean, it was slick.
This one was messy.
This was a messy win.
Still a good win, though.
I was so confused by the past 30 minutes.
Me too.
Me too, trust me.
I was...
My brain was malfunctioning throughout all of that.
Please, no more Azazel.
Now I'm going to play more Azazel.
Spoon and belt make you faster because it's used to discipline kids.
Oh!
Oh, shit.
I see.
That makes sense.
Guys, I'm having fun with whatever I'm doing now.
I'm just going to keep doing what I do, okay?
I'm unlocking stuff, I'm getting places.
I'm going to try other characters, don't worry.
Didn't I run today with a new character, huh?
Actually, I didn't.
I won both with...
I think both were with Azazel.
Last time was with Lazarus.
Yeah.
Last time was Lazarus.
Oh, I also want to try greed mode, yeah.
And challenge.
Maybe we'll try both next time.
That sounds good.
Oh, yes.
It doesn't know about the control key.
Now I do.
Now it's time for the Silksong upload, right?
No.
It's actually not... because you asked?
Man, you had it.
You shouldn't have asked.
You messed up.
Not Silksong tomorrow.
I know I left it on a cliffhanger, don't worry.
I'm kidding.
Dude, Silksong is over.
What do you mean?
Didn't you watch the last episode?
We hit credits.
We're done.
It's time for the next game.
When do we start the stream?
Uh, in approximately two days.
That's when the stream starts.
Hold on.
I'll show you.
Oh, I can't put it on 99 on the timer.
That's too bad.
Ah, okay.
I guess nine hours is the limit on this timer.
That's fine.
What's the next game?
I don't know.
I guess you'll find out.
I'm just gonna release...
It's not gonna be a poll, though, this time.
For the next game after Silksong.
It's just gonna come out, okay?
The next Isaac Live is probably the day after tomorrow.
But don't hold me to it.
If you wanna be sure, join the Discord and look for the events tab in the top.
I always put it in about a day before.
At the latest.
Sometimes earlier.
Or you can check the schedule on Twitch.
I do try to put them in there, too.
But I also forget sometimes.
But Discord is definitely the best way to keep track.
I stopped streaming on YouTube for a couple of reasons.
Genius friends.
One, I wanted to stream in 4K.
But it turns out there's a lot of delay as well between what's happening.
And it's also much harder to stream there.
In terms of just interacting with the viewers and setting up customization for the streamer.
I also didn't like the fact that all the vods were stored as live on the channel.
Sometimes people ask me, where's the Minecraft playthrough?
Because they can't find it.
You gotta click on the live tab, you know?
It's just very obscure, the way that works.
This way I'm recording in full 4K.
I put it on YouTube, you know?
Afterwards, it's just a lot of reasons, I guess.
What are the stuff on the screen right now?
It's just some scribbled notes of the developer who made the game.
One of the first pages, I think, they ever, you know, scrambled something on in terms of coming up with the game?
I found it on YouTube or on Google.
I don't know what any of it means.
I'm not even sure any of this has any relevance to what's actually in the game now.
This is all like, you can call it concept art in a way.
More like concept scribbles.
I thought, you wrote those?
No, no, no.
I didn't write that.
This is the guy who made the game.
Who wrote this.
His handwriting.
It fits the vibe, right?
That's what I thought.
I thought it was cool.
Edmund Macmillan.
Yeah, that guy.
It's from the official art book, by the way.
Oh, okay.
Well, there you go.
I did know that Super Meat Boy and Isaac were the same creator, yes.
Someone told me at some point.
What's your favorite item from today?
Uh, what is my favorite item?
God, I don't even remember half the items I got, because I got so many new ones.
Remind me some of the highlights that I got.
I mean, recency bias.
Oh, mod spider.
Yeah, that one was insane.
I want to have that again.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Spider mod, for sure.
The one that shows the health bars and all that, that was cool.
The purple fly?
I think that one did more than I noticed.
It was definitely absorbing shots and all that.
You can click control to change health pills or cards if you have multiple.
Okay, thank you.
That's a good tip.
I appreciate that.
Can you guess the lore of this game?
Yeah.
Isaac's mother is a fucking religious fanatic, who made sure that Isaac had a horrible childhood.
And it's just been pure hell ever since birth for him.
And he's trying to escape his mom by running into the basement.
And he's crying a lot, because his mom is evil, and it's just a shitty existence.
And he's seeing all these other evil things in the basement that makes him cry even more.
It pretty much made him into a... a messed up kid, you know?
Like, it made him completely fucked up in the head.
And that's why he's doing all these weird things.
Yeah.
That's why he's putting clothes hangers through his head.
It's why he's naked.
He runs around with his butt out.
You know?
He's running from belts.
Stuff like that.
Don't let me know, though.
I'm gonna probably figure it out as we go along.
Quite accurate.
I mean, it's literally in the intro cinematic, yeah.
I'm being told what the story is, you know?
You didn't know he was naked until recently?
Haven't you noticed he doesn't wear any clothes?
I mean, he's not wearing a jacket or pants, you know, or a hat or anything.
Sometimes he wears a hat.
The coat hanger is a reference to homemade abortions where they shove the coat hanger in there?
Fuck me.
I didn't want to know that.
That's terrible.
My god.
That is actually horrible.
You think that Silksong is better than Hollow Knight?
And the point of the history that you're in is hard to say.
I think I like it more than Hollow Knight simply because the combat is more fun.
I did enjoy figuring out the lore more in Hollow Knight, though.
But I also enjoyed just having it served to me in this one, right?
That's also cool.
But I definitely took more notes and I was going a little more slow because it paid off more in Hollow Knight.
In this one, I'm just sort of...
I guess I like the combat so much more in this one.
That the story is less important to me.
I just really enjoy the combat.
Will you do anything on April Fool's?
Yeah, your mom.
Sorry.
I'm not.
I'm kidding.
No, no.
I'm...
You know what?
I'm just going to make my exit right now.
Thank you everyone for watching.
I'll see you in the next three.
I'm not kidding.
I'm leaving.
Goodbye.
Time to eat and enjoy the Saturday.
You guys enjoy your Saturday, okay?
Have a wonderful Saturday, and I'm sure your mom is great.
Don't worry.
I did not do your mom.
Everything's cool between us.
I'll see you.
Bye-bye.